<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<search>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Passer-by</title>
    <link href="/2025/07/11/Passer-by/"/>
    <url>/2025/07/11/Passer-by/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>我打江南走过，那等在季节里的容颜如莲花般开落<br>郑愁予，<em>错误</em></p></blockquote><h1 id="Music-and-Society-Episode-9-A-mistake"><a href="#Music-and-Society-Episode-9-A-mistake" class="headerlink" title="Music and Society, Episode 9: A mistake"></a>Music and Society, Episode 9: A mistake</h1><h2 id="The-poem"><a href="#The-poem" class="headerlink" title="The poem"></a>The poem</h2><p>A few nights ago I had a dream about this poem. The focus was on complicated <em>intimate relationships</em>, as I always interpret this poem.</p><p>The poet, <strong>郑愁予</strong>(1933-2025), passed away on 13th June 2025. <strong>错误</strong>(a Mistake) was one of his most famous work. As a member from the older generations who fled to <em>Taiwan</em> and spent the majority of their career across the trait and ocean, he was appreciated by both side of the trait and later served as a <strong>cultural bridge</strong> in greater Chinese community. His poems were widely composed into songs by Taiwanese musicians, while Mainland schools had his works selected into textbooks. Unfortunately people like him are gradually passing away. (i.e. 陈彼得, passed on 14th June)</p><p>Zheng got his penname from 楚辞:</p><blockquote><p>帝子降兮北渚, 目眇眇兮愁予</p></blockquote><p>I had the strongest emotional swings learning these literatures during high school, including <em>公无渡河, 边城</em>, especially when teacher <strong>Tong</strong> asked us to read it out loud. They offered me huge sense of <strong>Xiang</strong> self-identity, provincial pride, and eager to recite them in dialect. I can still vividly see LiuYX trying to read while Tong seemed not satisfied.</p><h2 id="The-songs"><a href="#The-songs" class="headerlink" title="The songs"></a>The songs</h2><p>Two of the greatest musicians of that time composed 错误 into songs. It was a tradition during that period, as advocates of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Campus_folk_song"><strong>民歌运动</strong></a>, people were writing <strong><em>OUR OWN SONGS</em></strong>, and one of the most convenient ways was to use local poems as lyrics. <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lo_Ta-yu"><strong>罗大佑</strong></a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Li_Tai-hsiang"><strong>李泰祥</strong></a> transferred this 1952-published poem into songs respectively in 1982 and 1985, where Li even made a whole album based on Zheng’s works.</p><p>Here are the two versions:</p><iframe width="100%" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/yCRWlbSsQLE" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe><p>Soft, slow, reserved, with gentle clatter of hooves, walking as a free-spirited lighthearted traveler.</p><iframe width="100%" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Be3L_tLFph0" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe><p>Intense, grande, emotional, dramatic, with compelling storytelling progressing towards tragedy.</p><h2 id="Me"><a href="#Me" class="headerlink" title="Me"></a>Me</h2><p>I guess the most famous line of this poem/song is:</p><blockquote><p>我达达的马蹄是美丽的错误<br>我不是归人，是个过客…</p></blockquote><p>Notable interpretation was around <strong>post-war</strong> mixed emotions of <em>hope and confusion</em>. People like to add their own understanding, especially around the words <em>归人(the one who is returning home), 过客(the one who is passing by)</em>. I first had a strong connection to those two words on a pre-lockdown February/March afternoon in Roma on a bridge over <strong>Aniene</strong>. With a global incident pending, one started to question his own paths: in that relationship, <em>what roles do we play in each other’s life?</em></p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Music and Society</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Death of a Footballer</title>
    <link href="/2025/07/03/Death-of-a-Footballer/"/>
    <url>/2025/07/03/Death-of-a-Footballer/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I was having trouble sleeping while the news of <strong>Diogo Jota</strong> popped on my phone screen, and I could not go to sleep anymore.</p><p>There was not too much personal feeling. I thought of <strong>Liverpool fans</strong> immediately, and imagined how bad they were feeling at the moment. I though of possible <strong>cynical</strong> comments on social media, as I witnessed so many kinds of news recently ended up being flooded by people complaining about <strong>wealth imbalance</strong>. I observed <strong>X and Instagram</strong>, going through all kinds of posts from reporters, news agencies, players, legends, and felt a bit of relief, when all Premier League clubs posted their condolences <strong>respectfully after</strong> Liverpool released their official statement, roughly 1 hour after the first piece of news came out. I found out people criticizing the use of languages like <strong>“rivalry aside”, “although I am a xxx fan”</strong>, and could not decide what I should feel about those comments anymore.</p><p>One cynical but yet somehow justifiable lines of reasoning would be: why feel so sad for a millionaire thousands mile away for his potentially recklessly driving a Lamborghini that you won’t afford for rest of your life?</p><p>This is where football, this <strong>beautiful sports that connects people as a <strong>global community</strong></strong>, comes to play. One enjoys tremendous amount of joy, passion, and sorrow for the team and players they love. The ball game is a part of their lives, no matter what backgrounds, and as fellow football fans, we can always <strong>sympathize</strong>.</p><p>There were quite a few tragic accidents happened to footballers in recent years: <strong>Emiliano Sala, Davide Astori, Reyes</strong>… The shockest one to me was the helicopter crash of former <strong>Leicester</strong> boss <strong>Vichai</strong>. It happened during the midnight of change of Daylight Saving Time, and I was, like always, sleepless, in my dorm in Rome. They are different people from different clubs, it was the passion and the joy they brought to the community that made people so emotional.</p><p>One particular footballer’s passing had the strongest personal emotional impact on me: <strong>Walter Martínez</strong>, known as 小马丁 to fans of <strong>Beijing Guoan</strong>. I have talked about my identity crisis, and it was teams like Guoan that brought me a <strong>sense of belongingness</strong> for me to the city of Beijing. As an elementary student, I may have not seen much Guoan’s game in person or even on TV, I always hear those names: Xu Liang, Walter Martínez, Joel Griffiths, 我爱小马丁(a fan) on the sports broadcast, and feel for every game they (or we) won and lost. I was in Beijing on the day the news was out. Martínez and I are both outsiders that had the pleasure to feel somehow belonging to this city.</p><p>Death is always a tragic thing, and it makes you think more about what they have brought to people.</p><p>What a beautiful song</p><iframe width="100%" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/2ps-ckAwG-g" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe><blockquote><p>ᴏʜ, ʜᴇ ᴡᴇᴀʀꜱ ᴛʜᴇ ɴᴜᴍʙᴇʀ 20,<br>ʜᴇ ᴡɪʟʟ ᴛᴀᴋᴇ ᴜꜱ ᴛᴏ ᴠɪᴄᴛᴏʀʏ,<br>ᴀɴᴅ ᴡʜᴇɴ ʜᴇ’ꜱ ʀᴜɴɴɪɴɢ ᴅᴏᴡɴ ᴛʜᴇ ʟᴇꜰᴛ ᴡɪɴɢ,<br>ʜᴇ’ʟʟ ᴄᴜᴛ ɪɴꜱɪᴅᴇ ᴀɴᴅ ꜱᴄᴏʀᴇ ꜰᴏʀ ʟꜰᴄ.<br>ʜᴇ’ꜱ ᴀ ʟᴀᴅ ꜰʀᴏᴍ ᴘᴏʀᴛᴜɢᴀʟ,<br>ʙᴇᴛᴛᴇʀ ᴛʜᴀɴ ꜰɪɢᴏ ᴅᴏɴ’ᴛ ʏᴏᴜ ᴋɴᴏᴡ,<br>ᴏʜ, ʜɪꜱ ɴᴀᴍᴇ ɪꜱ ᴅɪᴏɢᴏ!!</p></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Sports</category>
      
      <category>Football</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Ode to the Peony</title>
    <link href="/2025/06/05/Ode-to-the-Peony/"/>
    <url>/2025/06/05/Ode-to-the-Peony/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>啊~啊~牡丹~百花丛中最鲜艳！<br>(Ah~ah~Peony~the most radiant among all flowers!)<br><em>The song of the peony (牡丹之歌)</em> by <em>Jiang Dawei (蒋大为)</em>, 1980</p></blockquote><p>At dawn on June 1st, 250 of 800 peony plants were found <a href="https://www.mlive.com/news/ann-arbor/2025/06/vandalism-of-university-of-michigan-peonies-was-in-support-of-palestine-police-confirm.html">vandalized</a>, cut down, in the W.E. Upjohn Peony Garden of the <a href="https://maps.app.goo.gl/tq8XZAiFghU3EC5Z6">University of Michigan Nichols Arboretum</a>.</p><p>While the police is actively investigating the incident, they have confirmed that the vandalization was done as a form of political protest related to the middle east. The Arboretum has released a <a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/DKXFSz5OFl7/?utm_source=ig_web_copy_link&igsh=MzRlODBiNWFlZA==">statement</a> to the community, saying <strong>“this resilient garden endures. The roots remain strong, and the garden will bloom again. And we will continue to honor this space and all that it means to those who find peace and joy here.”</strong></p><p>I was shocked by this news on Sunday morning, and visited the garden later in the afternoon. It made me <strong>sad and angry</strong> seeing hundreds of blossoms cut down, yet it made me comforted to realized that the other half of the peonies are standing <strong>strong and beautiful</strong> while hundreds of Ann Arbor residents are there, <em>appreciating their resilience and showing their support to the community</em>.</p><p>The <strong>Peony Garden</strong> carries special meanings for me. I had not known about the place until the summer of 2023, but it became the <strong>favorite place</strong> for me and my family in AA. It is a <strong>spiritual sanctuary</strong> where you connect with the nature and share energy to grow strong.</p><p>The main species, peony, also make things special. My home back in Beijing is close to somewhere called <strong>牡丹园</strong>(Peony Garden), where the same-name subway station is where I came home to every day. So, peonies are <strong>blooming</strong> in two of the most important town I have lived in. In addition, it’s needless to point out what Peonies represent in Chinese culture, <em>Prosperity and Harmony</em>.</p><p>Finally, a short message to my anger and confusion on vandalizing flowers as a protest:</p><p>Attacking something that most people love and cannot fight back is not realizing your goal. I may understand the metaphor and irony that were implied (e.g. flowers can bloom again, yet human lives cannot). What confused me most is that, <strong>flowers are used as spiritual symbols for all kinds of ideologies across the spectrum</strong>: Rose, Carnation, Chrysanthemum, Sakura, Tulip, Sunflower, Edelweiss, etc… No matter what message is expressed, an <strong>ALIVE</strong> and&#x2F;or blooming flower is used, while the choice depends on the color, shape, and cultural&#x2F;botanical situation. The <strong>“Flowers will bloom again”</strong> nature is used exactly as a symbol for whoever’s resilient <strong>ideal</strong>. Not the other way.</p><p>Let me again quote the director of the Arb, Tony Kolenic: <strong><em>“The roots remain strong, and the garden will bloom again.”</em></strong></p><p>P.S. This is a special episode of <strong>Music and Society</strong> for the Peony, we will talk about more songs of flowers next time.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Music and Society</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Ding Junhui&#39;s Curse: A Data Analysis</title>
    <link href="/2025/03/21/Ding-Junhui-s-Curse-A-Data-Analysis/"/>
    <url>/2025/03/21/Ding-Junhui-s-Curse-A-Data-Analysis/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>He who beats Ding this round, next round, shall not pass</p></blockquote><p><img src="/images/dingmeme.jpg" alt="A meme of the Ding&#39;s Curse"></p><p>An interesting pattern on <strong>World Snooker Tour</strong> has come to fans’ attention lately. Basically, since 2024 Player Championship, in the last 20 tournaments that <strong>Ding Junhui</strong> played in, <em>the opponent who beat him would be knocked out in the very next match</em>.</p><p>This trend was first noticed by Chinese fans last year, when people called it <strong>“The 1st Law of Ding Junhui”</strong>. It drew more attention from English-speaking fans recently. In particular, <strong>Shaun Murphy</strong> mentioned it in the <a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/2MDiuKCEzwoxqFRn9cXm6T">onefourseven Snooker Podcast</a>. Detailed lists of who Ding lost to and how they got beaten in the next round were compiled by multiple sources, you may find one in Chinese <a href="https://weibo.com/5718804188/PjnyS2lI8">here</a> on Weibo, and one in English <a href="https://metro.co.uk/2025/03/14/ding-junhui-curse-haunts-this-snooker-season-can-break-22722452/">here</a> on Metro.</p><p>This Law, or curse, works not only in normal way, such as whoever beat Ding in Quarter-final would got beaten in Semi-final, but also in mysterious ways. For example, in <strong>2024 World Open</strong>, Ding lost to <strong>Judd Trump</strong> in the final, and then Judd would later be beaten in the very first round of the very next tournament, <strong>Tour Championship</strong>. Also, in this year’s <strong>German Masters</strong>, where Ding withdrew from the tournament, <strong>Ross Muir</strong>, who received a bye against Ding, got knocked out in his next match.</p><p>Naturally, people start to wonder if Ding actually has some mysterious power, or it’s just coincidental. I made an analysis regarding all the <strong>WST</strong> players records during the time frame when Ding’s Curse worked 100% (2024 Player Championship to 2025 World Grand Prix) and find some interesting results. I gathered information from <a href="https://snooker.org">snooker.org</a>, you may find my source code <a href="https://github.com/Fredfreddo/Ding-Junhui-Curse-Analysis/blob/main/DingJunhui_Curse_Analysis.ipynb">here</a>.</p><h3 id="Definitions"><a href="#Definitions" class="headerlink" title="Definitions"></a>Definitions</h3><p>We keep track of the following features for each player P<sub>i</sub>:</p><ul><li>L<sub>i</sub>: total number of loss the player had in the time period. We only consider <strong>Knockout</strong> tournaments, so L<sub>i</sub> = A<sub>i</sub> - W<sub>i</sub>, where A<sub>i</sub> is how many tournaments the player played in, W<sub>i</sub> is number of champions the player won.</li><li>C<sub>i</sub>: count of <strong>Curse Success</strong>. A successful curse means that for player P<sub>j</sub> that P<sub>i</sub> lost against, P<sub>j</sub> loses their next match on Tour.</li><li>R<sub>i</sub>: World Ranking of the player, an integer larger than 0.</li></ul><blockquote><p>Based on L<sub>i</sub> and C<sub>i</sub>, we may calculate a <strong>Curse Success Rate</strong> CSR<sub>i</sub> = C<sub>i</sub>/L<sub>i</sub> for each player.<br>We know that for Ding Junhui, his CSR=<strong>100%</strong></p></blockquote><h3 id="Findings"><a href="#Findings" class="headerlink" title="Findings"></a>Findings</h3><p>From the data, we find out some players that are nearly as strong as a <strong>“Curser”</strong> like Ding Junhui:</p><ul><li><strong>Xiao Guodong</strong> and <strong>Andrew Higginson</strong>: Curse Rate (CSR) = 80% (12/15)</li><li><strong>Stephen Maguire</strong>, <strong>Ronnie O’Sullivan</strong>, <strong>Bulcsu Revesz</strong>, <strong>Sunny Akani</strong>: CSR = 75%</li></ul><p><strong><em>If one encountered those players above, one would likely not pass their next round.</em></strong></p><p>Also, there are some <strong>“Highly friendly players”</strong>, meaning that <strong><em>one would likely to win at least another match if one beat that player</em></strong></p><ul><li><strong>Alfie Burden</strong>. CSR = 1/15. Having lost match in 15 tournaments, only one time his opponent did not win next match.</li><li><strong>Graeme Dott</strong> (2/15), <strong>Wang Yuchen</strong> (3/13), <strong>Lei Peifan</strong> (4/13)</li></ul><h3 id="Visualization"><a href="#Visualization" class="headerlink" title="Visualization"></a>Visualization</h3><p>So, people are wondering if this <strong>Curse Success Rate</strong> has something to do with a player’s style or personality. I decided to plot players’ CSR against their rankings, a good measurement of a player’s strength.</p><p><img src="/images/curse_success_ratio_vs_ranking.png" alt=""></p><p><strong>No</strong> obvious trend or pattern could be seen here. One may argue there might be a trend within some certain groups of lower ranked players. Ding Junhui, Graeme Dott, and Alfie Burden are clearly shown as <strong>outliers</strong>.</p><p>Most players’ CSR fall within the range 40%~60%. This is aligned with the nature of the CSR we calculated. In each <strong>non-first-round</strong> match in a knockout tournament, both players had beaten someone else in the previous round. So, for the two players beaten last round, there are exactly one successful “curse” and one failed “curse”. Therefore, overall the <strong>expected CSR</strong> for a random player should be <strong>50%</strong>. However, in some Snooker tournaments, <strong>tiered knockout system</strong> were used, where not all players have a “previously beaten opponent” and players who beat someone to play against a higher-ranked player are likely to be beaten, the overall CSR are slightly over 50% as shown in the plot.</p><p>A histogram of CSR:</p><p><img src="\images\curse_success_ratio_distribution.png" alt=""></p><p>So, is it coincidental or something special? If special, Murphy and some fans argued that maybe <em>“it <strong>took so much energy</strong> to beat Ding that the player could not achieve his best in the next round”</em>, while some Chinese fans joked that <em>“Beating Ding creates such an <strong>illusional sense of accomplishment</strong> so that the player became over-confident next round”</em></p><p>For me, I like this redditor’s <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/snooker/comments/1jgkff5/comment/mizymn3/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button">words</a>: <strong>“It’d be funny if it becomes a self fulfilling prophecy and people start bottling matches because they beat Ding”</strong></p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Sports</category>
      
      <category>Snooker</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Rebel Girls</title>
    <link href="/2025/03/07/Rebel-Girls/"/>
    <url>/2025/03/07/Rebel-Girls/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>It is a universal campaign for equality, justice, and humanity, where no person will be forced into a compromised position ever again.</p></blockquote><p>I am using this episode of Music and Society to commemorate <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/International_Women%27s_Day">International Women’s Day</a>, with 3 songs honoring Women’s fight in history.</p><h1 id="Music-and-Society-Episode-8-March-8th-Special"><a href="#Music-and-Society-Episode-8-March-8th-Special" class="headerlink" title="Music and Society, Episode 8: March 8th Special"></a>Music and Society, Episode 8: March 8th Special</h1><h2 id="La-Lega"><a href="#La-Lega" class="headerlink" title="La Lega"></a>La Lega</h2><blockquote><p>Sebben che siamo donne<br>Paura non abbiamo</p></blockquote><iframe width="100%" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/uUIbEIVPTR8" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe><p>It’s an <strong>Italian</strong> folk song written in 19th century. The writer is unknown. It is about the <strong>revolt of female agricultural workers</strong> against their bosses. I first heard it from Italian TV, when I was struck by the <strong><em>unified, optimistic, determined, elated</em></strong> voice. The above was a clip of this song in the famous movie <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/1900_(film)">1900</a></p><h2 id="Bread-and-Roses"><a href="#Bread-and-Roses" class="headerlink" title="Bread and Roses"></a>Bread and Roses</h2><blockquote><p>As we come marching, marching, we bring the Greater Days<br>The rising of the women means the rising of the race<br>No more the drudge and idler: ten that toil where one reposes<br>But a sharing of life’s glories: Bread and Roses, Bread and Roses</p></blockquote><iframe width="100%" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/YsvGPj0LH0M" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe><p>An iconic poet written by <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/James_Oppenheim">James Oppenheim</a>. It is composed and sung by multiple celebrated musicians. I first heard of this song in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Elizabeth_Gurley_Flynn">Elizabeth Gurley Flynn</a>‘s autobiography <strong>Rebel Girl</strong>, where she mentioned the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/1912_Lawrence_textile_strike">Textile Strike</a> in Lawrence, Massachusetts, 1912. The poet (lyrics) is not only about female workers fighting for better <strong>pay</strong> and <strong>dignified working conditions</strong>, but also highly aligned with the <strong>suffrage movement</strong> at the time. The metaphor of Bread and Roses added a sense of <strong>gentle resilience</strong> to the strength and spirits of those who fight. And it partly contributed to the legacy of Roses being the symbol of these movements.</p><h2 id="Rebel-Girl"><a href="#Rebel-Girl" class="headerlink" title="Rebel Girl"></a>Rebel Girl</h2><blockquote><p>That’s the Rebel Girl, the Rebel Girl!<br>To the working class, she’s a precious pearl.<br>…<br>For it’s great to fight for freedom<br>With a Rebel Girl.</p></blockquote><iframe width="100%" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/cN_h5V8Eo-I" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe><p>Yes, it’s about <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Elizabeth_Gurley_Flynn">Elizabeth Gurley Flynn</a>, the leading figure of 20th century movements for labor rights and women suffrage. A song of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Joe_Hill_(activist)">Joe Hill</a>. We can talk about him another day.</p><p>Yes, I heard it first from the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kaiserreich_(mod)">HOI4 mod Kaiserreich</a>. For one time the game ended where all leaders of major countries are women. It is too <em>magical</em> to imagine.</p><p>Yes, like it said, it is a fight for all people against all forms of <em>oppression</em>. One does not have to be in a specific identity to feel that, as it is universal.</p><h3 id="P-S"><a href="#P-S" class="headerlink" title="P.S."></a>P.S.</h3><p>Yeah, I know, they are songs 100 years ago. But hey, we are still fighting for these, today.</p><p>So, here is an homage to all the <strong><em>Rebel Girls</em></strong>, who are making us a better world.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Music and Society</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Bridge and Mixed Strategy, an Example</title>
    <link href="/2025/03/03/Bridge-and-Mixed-Strategy-an-Example/"/>
    <url>/2025/03/03/Bridge-and-Mixed-Strategy-an-Example/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I heard about this fascinating board from <a href="https://github.com/spade14">Spade14</a>, one of the best bridge mentors I have ever had.</p><h2 id="Problem"><a href="#Problem" class="headerlink" title="Problem"></a>Problem</h2><p>The board information is embedded in this <a href="https://www.bridgebase.com/tools/hvdoc.html">Handviewer</a> tool of <a href="https://www.bridgebase.com/">BridgeBaseOnline</a>. You can navigate through the auctions and playing by clicking the buttons.</p><iframe src="https://www.bridgebase.com/tools/handviewer.html?s=sQJT98ha2dak32c45&n=s765hq345678d4ckj&d=s&a=1s{12 to 21 high card points, 5+!S}p2s{Simple raise, usually 8 to 10 with 3!S}p3d(invitation){South chooses to invite North to game}p4s{Feeling the !H suit and singleton !D could be useful, North bids game}ppp&v=b&p=s2{West leads a trump}s5{The declarer has 2 !S losers, 1 !H loser, potentially 2 !D loser, and 2 !C losers. The contract is in jeopardy.}sas8sks9s3s6s4{Three rounds of !S cleared East-West's trump, but also smashed dummy's ruffing ability}stc2{!C2 was indicated as encouraging !D}s7hah9h3hjh2hth4hk{Lucky for South that !H are 2-2}dj{!DJ denies Q}dad5d4{Already losing 3 tricks, the declarer now wants to sneak into dummy and cash all North's !H winners}c4{Now what West should do?}&b=7" height="300px" width="100%"/></iframe><p>In short, South reached a difficult 4&spades; with 7 potential losers. After 6 rounds, they have a chance to minimize the damage or even make the contract.</p><p>The situation sounds obvious: either East or West has &clubs;A, which will be the 4th trick for them, beating the contract.</p><p>Here’s the catch: <strong>West wants more.</strong></p><p>What are the common knowledge all players have at this point?</p><ul><li>South has the 2 remaining &spades;;</li><li>North has all the remaining &hearts;;</li><li>If South has &clubs;A, the contract is making;<ul><li>based on this, defenders need to assume South does not have &clubs;A;</li><li>That means South must have &diams;AK, making 14 points in total, a reasonable inviting hand;</li><li>The location of &clubs;Q is unclear to defenders. But if South has it, they must be an unbalanced hand or they would have opened 1NT (15-17).</li></ul></li></ul><p>Let’s picture 4 different hands that West might be holding at this point (after 6 rounds):</p><iframe src="https://www.bridgebase.com/tools/handviewer.html?w=dq76caq67" height="180px" width="180px"/></iframe><iframe src="https://www.bridgebase.com/tools/handviewer.html?w=dq76c9867" height="180px" width="180px"/></iframe><iframe src="https://www.bridgebase.com/tools/handviewer.html?w=dq76c8q67" height="180px" width="180px"/></iframe><iframe src="https://www.bridgebase.com/tools/handviewer.html?w=dq76ca867" height="180px" width="180px"/></iframe><ul><li>1, With both &clubs;AQ, West has no choice but to play the &clubs;A, as playing any other card would make an entry for North, enabling the declarer to cash all the &hearts;;</li><li>2, With neither &clubs;A or &clubs;Q, West may easily play a small card. North can never cash the &hearts; as East can overtake North’s &clubs;. The declarer will lose 2 &spades;, 1 &hearts;, 2&diams;, 2 &clubs;: down 4, 400 points to East-West;</li><li>3, With &clubs;Q, West would still play a small card, leaving the guess to South. Had South played J, finessing the Q, East would take with the &clubs;A: down 1, 100 for East-West; Had South played K, guessing wrong, it would be down 4, 400 points for East-West;</li></ul><p>In the first 3 scenarios, West has clear <strong>Dominant Strategy</strong>. Here comes the scenario No.4:</p><blockquote><p>With &clubs;A in West and &clubs;Q in East</p></blockquote><h2 id="End-Game"><a href="#End-Game" class="headerlink" title="End Game"></a>End Game</h2><p>The remaining cards are:</p><iframe src="https://www.bridgebase.com/tools/handviewer.html?s=sQJhdk32c5&n=shq5678dckj&w=dq76ca867&e=shdt98cqt93&b=7&v=b&d=s&a=1sp2sp3d(invitation)p4sppp" height="300px" width="100%"/></iframe><p>West has two options:</p><ul><li>Play &clubs;A. This will guarantee down 1 as the result. (Now North has the entry to cash &hearts;)</li><li>Take the risk and play a small &clubs;:<ul><li>if declarer plays K, they will take all the remaining tricks, making 4&spades;, +620 for North-South</li><li>if declarer plays J, East can win with Q. West’s A can take over dummy’s K, forcing South to have 7 losers in total: +400 for East-West</li></ul></li></ul><p>To be safe, West should play &clubs;A to guarantee a positive score for their team. <strong>This</strong>, gives South an advantage: <strong><em>When West plays small, South will know that West does not have A</em></strong>, so South will definitely play &clubs;J to minimize the damage to -100.</p><p><strong>However</strong>, knowing <strong><em>South will play J if West plays small</em></strong>, West can use it to break their consistent playing A and play a small, triggering South to play J and making East-West maximize their gain to +400.</p><p>Without dominant strategy in this scenario, here come bluffing and gambling.</p><h2 id="Mixed-Strategy"><a href="#Mixed-Strategy" class="headerlink" title="Mixed Strategy"></a>Mixed Strategy</h2><p>We can draw an Outcome Table in this scenario:</p><style type="text/css">.tg  {border-collapse:collapse;border-spacing:0;}.tg td{border-color:black;border-style:solid;border-width:1px;font-family:Arial, sans-serif;font-size:14px;  overflow:hidden;padding:10px 5px;word-break:normal;}.tg th{border-color:black;border-style:solid;border-width:1px;font-family:Arial, sans-serif;font-size:14px;  font-weight:normal;overflow:hidden;padding:10px 5px;word-break:normal;}.tg .tg-0pky{border-color:inherit;text-align:left;vertical-align:top}</style><table class="tg"><thead>  <tr>    <th class="tg-0pky">West Plays &darr; \ Dummy plays &rarr;</th>    <th class="tg-0pky">&clubs;K</th>    <th class="tg-0pky">&clubs;J</th>  </tr></thead><tbody>  <tr>    <td class="tg-0pky">&clubs;A</td>    <td class="tg-0pky">Impossible for a sober declarer</td>    <td class="tg-0pky">(NS-100, EW+100)</td>  </tr>  <tr>    <td class="tg-0pky">Small &clubs;</td>    <td class="tg-0pky">(NS+620, EW-620)</td>    <td class="tg-0pky">(NS-400, EW+400)</td>  </tr></tbody></table><p>to be continued;</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Bridge</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Spring in the North, Youth from the South</title>
    <link href="/2025/02/23/Spring-in-the-North-Youth-from-the-South/"/>
    <url>/2025/02/23/Spring-in-the-North-Youth-from-the-South/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Two songs</strong> appear frequently in my life recently in two totally different ways. It only strikes me tonight that they shared similar <strong>sentiments, circumstances, and emotions</strong>. It’s my pleasure to bring together these two stories, <strong>32 years apart in two islands</strong>.</p><h1 id="Music-and-Society-Episode-7"><a href="#Music-and-Society-Episode-7" class="headerlink" title="Music and Society, Episode 7"></a>Music and Society, Episode 7</h1><h3 id="北国の春-南国的孩子"><a href="#北国の春-南国的孩子" class="headerlink" title="北国の春 &amp; 南国的孩子"></a>北国の春 &amp; 南国的孩子</h3><h4 id="Spring-in-the-North"><a href="#Spring-in-the-North" class="headerlink" title="Spring in the North:"></a>Spring in the North:</h4><blockquote><p>白樺 青空 南風<br>亭亭白桦，悠悠碧空，微微南来风<br>White birches, azure sky, and breezes from the South</p></blockquote><p><strong>Spring</strong>, such a mysterious thing. You never know when it comes quietly, along with warmer breeze and new <em>hope</em>.</p><p><strong>Ann Arbor</strong> is indeed still very cold. Last week we witnessed one of the <em>heaviest</em> snow storm I have been through in these years, but this weekend, traces of spring began to <strong>sprout</strong>.</p><p>The <strong>snow</strong> piled up along the curbs is silently melting, the <strong>wind</strong> is no longer freezing but has a neutral gentle touch, flocks of <strong>ducks, geese, and swans</strong> are forced out of thick ice on the banks of the Huron river, chasing each other along the water flows…</p><p>Although there’s no birch tree exactly and the sky is not exactly azure but a bit white, N’s urge to sing <strong><em>北国之春</em></strong> out loud is perfectly justifiable.</p><p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5NvRyAn6jWQ"><strong><em>北国の春</em></strong></a>, a song of <em>千昌夫</em> released in 1977, is an all-time Japanese classic. The song is translated and sung all over East Asia and has great popularity. For Chinese listeners, the first popular versions might be <strong><em>Teresa Teng</em></strong>‘s covers in 1979 and 1984 in Mandarin and Japanese. However, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=z0tCpDY2Ong">Teng’s Chinese version</a> did not reflect the original meanings of the Japanese lyrics.</p><p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2Ub4jhqOPgc">Another version</a>, more familiar to the Mainland Chinese audience, is written by <strong>吕远</strong> (Lyu Yuan) and performed by <strong>蒋大为</strong> (Jiang Dawei) in 1987. The lyrics kept the meanings of the original ones, which is about</p><blockquote><p>A Wanderer, an expat, or a worker or student away from home (<strong><em>游子</em></strong>)<br>Living in a northern territory, perhaps a big metropolitan, cold and unfamiliar<br>When the winter is transitioning into spring<br>They think about their parents, their lover who are set apart<br>and the Hometown they left to fight for…</p></blockquote><p>How suitable to the current situation. Or should I say, it’s always like this?</p><p>A side note: Lyu Yuan and Jiang Dawei are both famous for producing mostly <strong><em>mainstream</em></strong> songs in China. Having this particular song re-translated and covered is somehow a reflection of the openness and the Sino-Japanese relationship during that era.</p><h4 id="Youth-from-the-South"><a href="#Youth-from-the-South" class="headerlink" title="Youth from the South:"></a>Youth from the South:</h4><blockquote><p>你是南國來的孩子 有著不能縛的性子<br>身上披覆了寓言而渾然不知<br>奔跑著 忘我的 快樂悲傷都放肆<br>陽光也不願阻止</p></blockquote><blockquote><p>You are a son of the South, untamed, destined by the fables yet unaware,<br>Running, lost in fierce freedom no matter joy or sorrow,<br>That the Sun and you are reluctant to stop each other…</p></blockquote><p>Why this song? I only have <em>Spotify</em> to blame.</p><p>She is known by two names: <strong>安溥、张悬</strong> (Deserts Chang &#x2F; Anpu). Personally, for a long time, my few impression of her had been the beautiful song <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Q-zTDbTsYnU"><strong>宝贝</strong></a>, the <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/world-asia-pacific-24856658"><strong>National Flag incident during the concert in 2013</strong></a>, and the <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=CMH-VJ9cvG8">banned song</a> written for social activists.</p><p>She stepped away from public for awhile and faded in my knowledge too during the time, until one day I added all her songs into my Spotify list as well as a few favorite singers, which leads to this occasional burst of broadcasting in my random shuffling player…</p><p>Back to <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=adFuFp672jM">the song</a>. It is another perfect example of our topic: Music and Society. According to Anpu’s interviews, it is written for the <strong>indigenous</strong> people of the Island, as well as for <em>the people, willingly or forced, fighting for a living in an unfamiliar land and trying to gain a sense of dignity and happiness</em>.</p><blockquote><p>They are sons and daughter of the South<br>Wounded by the overwhelming shocks of the New World,<br>Blood oozed from the wound, carrying the ancient souls from home<br>or something Unknown…</p></blockquote><p>It might be some universal feelings shared by lots of wanderers around the globe, or perhaps everyone has a bit different tale to tell. Just hope, from time to time, year to year, when one senses the signals of the spring from the <em>birch trees, azure sky, and southern breeze</em>, one may recall this <strong><em>Unknown yet Similar</em></strong> feeling…</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Music and Society</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>About Me</title>
    <link href="/2025/01/08/About-Me/"/>
    <url>/2025/01/08/About-Me/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="About-Me"><a href="#About-Me" class="headerlink" title="About Me"></a>About Me</h2><img src="/images/snowman.jpg" title="A regular image" width="204px" height="357px" style="float:right"><p>I am <strong>Fangqing Yuan</strong>, graduated from <strong>University of Michigan, Ann Arbor</strong> with a <strong>Master in Data Science</strong>. I received my Bachelor degree at <strong>LUISS Guido Carli</strong>, Rome, Italy, where I studied <strong>Management and Computer Science</strong> and had spent one semester at <strong>KU Leuven</strong>, Belgium. I worked as a <strong>Machine Learning Engineer</strong> intern at <a href="https://www.kuaishou.com/en"><strong>Kuaishou</strong></a> in 2023, focusing on <strong>Social and User Relationship Recommendation Algorithms</strong>.</p><p>I am open for opportunities in <strong>Data Science, Statistics, and Computer Science</strong>. My research focused on <strong>Causal Inference, Recommender System, Time Series Analysis, Natural Language Processing, Survey Methodology</strong>, and a particular interest in applying statistical methods to competitive game strategies.</p><p>You may find my full CV <a href="https://github.com/Fredfreddo/resume/blob/main/Yuan_Fangqing_CV.pdf"><strong>HERE</strong></a>. And my <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/fangqing-yuan/"><strong>LinkedIn Profile</strong></a>.</p><p>You may find my selected papers and projects here:</p><ul><li><a href="https://github.com/Fredfreddo/CausalInferenceSocialMedia/blob/main/capstone_fangqing_yuan.pdf">Impact of Ranking-Boosting Strategies in Friend Recommender Systems on User Activeness in Kuaishou Social Networks</a> (Master Program Capstone Project Paper, inspired by my <strong>Internship</strong> at the <strong>User Relationship Recommendation</strong> team at <strong>Kuaishou</strong>)</li><li><a href="https://tesi.luiss.it/31912/">Regression analysis of contract bridge hand evaluation and its application on bidding</a> (Bachelor Degree Thesis)</li><li><a href="https://github.com/Fredfreddo/STATS531_final">Stochastic Modeling of MERS-CoV Transmission Dynamics </a></li><li><a href="https://github.com/Fredfreddo/Models-and-Analysis-of-WannaCry-propagation">Visualization and vaccination analysis computer virus propagation based on Sublinear Preferential Attachment Network</a></li><li><a href="https://github.com/Fredfreddo/stats531_midterm">Analysis of Battery-Powered Electric Vehicles Sales in the United States</a></li><li><a href="https://fredfreddo.github.io/2025/03/21/Ding-Junhui-s-Curse-A-Data-Analysis/">Data Analysis on Ding Junhui’s Curse</a></li><li><a href="https://fredfreddo.github.io/2025/03/03/Bridge-and-Mixed-Strategy-an-Example/">Bridge and Game Theory Mixed Strategy (<em>work in progress</em>)</a></li></ul><h2 id="About-this-Website"><a href="#About-this-Website" class="headerlink" title="About this Website"></a>About this Website</h2><p>Apart from this page, this website is mainly a <strong>personal blog</strong> of mine. I would share my passion in <strong>Bridge, Music, Books, Football(Soccer&#x2F;Calcio), Snooker</strong>, and lots of other thoughts, hobbies, and project. You may browse them by categories <a href="https://fredfreddo.github.io/categories/">here</a>.</p><h2 id="More-About-Me"><a href="#More-About-Me" class="headerlink" title="More About Me"></a>More About Me</h2><h3 id="Bridge"><a href="#Bridge" class="headerlink" title="Bridge"></a>Bridge</h3><p>I am decorated <strong>Bridge</strong> player. Having started learning bridge since 2011, I participated in countless tournaments and achieved multiple awards. My biggest awards include <strong>China U21 Champion</strong> in 2017, Runner-up in Junior group at <strong>Asian Bridge Congress</strong>, and twice the 3rd place in <strong>Junior United States Bridge Championship</strong> in 2022 and 2024. I also represented <strong>China U21 Team</strong> in <strong>2016 World Youth Bridge Team Championship</strong>.</p><p>Bridge is a life-long passion for me that sharpens my fast-paced real-time <strong>analysis, decision making, and game strategies</strong>. It gives me invaluable treasure of <strong>Partnership, Teamwork, and Friendship</strong>. Beyond playing, I conduct algorithmic research on bridge strategies; I contribute to bridge communities by mentoring in bridge clubs.</p><h3 id="Global-Experience"><a href="#Global-Experience" class="headerlink" title="Global Experience"></a>Global Experience</h3><p>I have academic and professional experience in China, Italy, Belgium, and the US. I believe in cultural exchanges and the power of diversity. I enjoy learning new cultures and languages.</p><h3 id="Passion"><a href="#Passion" class="headerlink" title="Passion"></a>Passion</h3><ul><li><p>I love <strong>music</strong>, especially pop songs and ballads in Mainland China, Hong Kong, and Taiwan.</p></li><li><p>I am a die-hard fan of <strong>AC Milan</strong>, Forza Milan! I enjoy watching European football in general and I love Football Manager games.</p></li><li><p>I follow <strong>Snooker</strong> closely, and am fan of <a href="https://fredfreddo.github.io/2024/01/19/Si-Jiahui/"><strong>Si Jiahui</strong></a>. I also enjoy applying analytics on sports, <a href="https://fredfreddo.github.io/2025/03/21/Ding-Junhui-s-Curse-A-Data-Analysis/">the data analysis on the “Ding Junhui’s Curse”</a> is an example on snooker.</p></li><li><p>My favorite authors are <strong>Yu Hua</strong> and <a href="https://fredfreddo.github.io/2019/01/11/visit-the-cemetery-of-italo-calvino-and-a-story-between-him-and-a-young-chinese-student/"><strong>Italo Calvino</strong></a>.</p></li><li><p>I am huge fan of <strong>Paradox Interactive</strong> grand strategy games, especially <strong>HOI4</strong> and <strong>EU4</strong>.</p></li></ul>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Self-Mumbling</category>
      
      <category>Who Am I</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>2024 Books</title>
    <link href="/2025/01/07/2024-Books/"/>
    <url>/2025/01/07/2024-Books/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="Books-I-read-in-2024"><a href="#Books-I-read-in-2024" class="headerlink" title="Books I read in 2024"></a>Books I read in 2024</h1><p><strong><em>Luckily</em></strong>, again, I did NOT have too much time to read this year, which could mean that I spent time on some serious business. This year, I would still categorize them into 3 classes: <strong><em>Queen, Ferrante, and Society</em></strong>.</p><h2 id="Ellery-Queen"><a href="#Ellery-Queen" class="headerlink" title="Ellery Queen"></a>Ellery Queen</h2><p>I finally finished the Drury Lane series: <strong>The Tragedy of X, the Tragedy of Y, the Tragedy of Z, Drury Lane’s last Case.</strong></p><p>I have two weird obsessions: <strong>Collections</strong> or Series of Books, and <strong>Golden Age</strong> detective novels. Ellery Queen’s work fits perfectly to these two requirements. Simply staring at their sets of “Tragedies” or “Country Names” series, or even just knowing they exist, would be extremely satisfying to me.</p><p>For years I have been dreaming to purchase and read a set of the “Tragedies” series in English. The books seemed to be too old and unpopular to have a <strong>modern printed edition</strong>, and my countless trips to <strong>second-handed bookstores</strong> all over the world proved to be fruitless, as my best buy was a copy of <strong><em>Greek Coffin Mystery</em></strong> printed in 1940s.</p><p>I had been told about the Chinese editions published by <strong>XinXing</strong> for a while, their colors were not bad (red, blue, yellow, I gather?), but I held my ground of <em>“not reading the Chinese translation if original English version is available”</em>. By the way, that rule costed me a lot of money and time…</p><p>Eventually I could not resist the temptation anymore during my last month in Beijing in 2023. By that time I realized even XinXing lost their publishing rights and that tricolor version was no longer on market. I paid an overcharged amount on <strong>孔夫子旧书网</strong> to buy an even earlier version printed by XinXing.</p><p>Anyway, the reading experience was satisfying. Those books served as a treasurable relaxation during the one last busy semester I’d probably ever have. I would not talk about the plots here, but I want to say a bit on <strong>Patience Thumm</strong>, the intelligent passionate daughter of Inspector Thumm from NYPD. Queen had the chance to expand this wonderful female detective character in their later works, but they opted to develop <strong>Ellery Queen</strong>, a cocky smart son of Richard Queen from NYPD. I would say the only essential difference was their gender. It is quite a pity, and it was sad to see some mean comments on Patience online. Just imagine what would happen.</p><h2 id="Elena-Ferrante"><a href="#Elena-Ferrante" class="headerlink" title="Elena Ferrante"></a>Elena Ferrante</h2><p>Another <strong><em>Quartet</em></strong> that I admired yet delayed to read: <strong>La Tetralogia Napoletana</strong>.</p><p>Like that rule, I always tell me not to read the Chinese version before I become <em>proficient</em> enough in Italian to read the original version. Well, that never happens.</p><p>So, <strong>那不勒斯四部曲</strong> came about the same time during late 2023 from online discounts. The translation by <strong>Chen Ying</strong> is so smooth that I immediately regretted not having read them earlier.</p><p>I am not sure how I should react about me somehow feeling related to the main characters. It could be the case, as mentioned in the third book, that a male person has projected certain ideal image on a female character and then somewhat enjoy the starting contract of her suffering and achievements since the male only actually has real experience on the good side. The words in the book were like: <strong>“The woman he would desire to become if he were born as a female.”</strong></p><h2 id="Society-and-Politics"><a href="#Society-and-Politics" class="headerlink" title="Society and Politics"></a>Society and Politics</h2><p>Interesting stuff in general, ordered by time finished reading (early to late):</p><ul><li><p><strong>1453</strong> by <em>Roger Crowley</em>. Story of the fall of Constantinople and the rise of Ottomans. Airplane reading I chose since I had to spend 8 hours in transit at <strong>Istanbul</strong> Airport. Nothing special. Recently came across a novel telling story about <strong>Castilian</strong> reconquering <strong>Granada</strong>, would be an intriguing comparison.</p></li><li><p><strong>中产阶级的孩子们</strong> by <em>程巍</em>. The Asian section of <strong>Hatcher Graduate Library</strong> has become of great source of relaxing and fulfilling my obsession on simply hanging around books. The title was more than appealing, but I was too little informed to get the content.</p></li><li><p><strong>多重奏(Sonic Multiplicities)</strong> by <em>周耀辉</em> and <em>Jeroen de Kloet</em>. Another treasure discovered in Hatcher, a collection of essays on <strong>Chinese pop music</strong> (CN, HK, TW) with topics related to <strong>Nationalism, Feminism, and Minorities</strong>. I had an article on this book <a href="https://fredfreddo.github.io/2024/05/31/Yellow-Faces/">here</a>. The book is no longer appearing on Douban, same were lots of other books.</p></li><li><p><strong>置身事内</strong> by <em>兰小欢</em>. I probably need more general readings on economics and finance.</p></li><li><p><strong>社会与政治运动讲义</strong> by <em>赵鼎新</em>. Reading those stuff kind of feels like fulfilling certain obsession… But things could surely evolve and adjust to new norms. Also, it can be highly related to what I seriously do, for example, during that symposium, listening to <em>Xu Xiaohong</em>‘s quantitative approach to analyze how CCP and KMT fought to win over the mass was quite interesting.</p></li><li><p><strong>May Made Me</strong> by <em>Mitchell Abidor</em>. A collection of interviews of students, workers, activists, and citizens on their recollections of <strong>May 68</strong>. I am still at a stage without non-vague political opinion, so reading those historical events was out of pure interest and “inertia”. Looking at how a group of people, who used to participate a significant history moment, turned out to be decades later was fascinating: some professors, some workers, some even EU Parliament member… Remembering <strong>Reed</strong>‘s account on 1917, most of the unknown names I came across in the book had the same result upon Google search: victim of <strong>The Great Purge</strong>. Just wonder what our generation would remember in the future? We are history of our own. <strong>“You have to rebel, even if you fail”</strong></p></li><li><p><strong>绿岛(Green island)</strong> by <em>杨小娜(Shawna Yang Ryan)</em>. I was looking for modern <strong>Taiwanese</strong> literature in Hatcher and this one came across. Full article about the book <a href="https://fredfreddo.github.io/2024/08/13/Green-Island/">here</a>. Some descriptions of then TW immigrants could highly match those of the nowadays Mainland immigrants…</p></li><li><p><strong>暴政史</strong> by <em>徐贲</em>. A great introductory book on tyranny and its history, also provided a bunch of further readings of memoirs and fictions. My article about the book <a href="https://fredfreddo.github.io/2024/09/28/Arms-Against-Tyranny/">here</a>.</p></li><li><p><strong>上海罢工(Shanghai on Strike: The Politics of Chinese Labor)</strong> by <em>裴宜理(Elizabeth Perry)</em>. Recently years Shanghai has become quite a magical city in my eyes. It’s international and diverse, full of immigrants from all provinces. Fellow <strong>Provincials</strong> establish their own community in a big city and support each other. Human has been doing these for hundreds of years, and I am still a part of this.</p></li><li><p><strong>六七暴動，香港戰後歷史的分水嶺(Hong Kong’s Watershed: The 1967 Riots)</strong> by <em>张家玮</em>. A pdf version book I started reading since 2019, when I finished reading <strong>1367</strong>, the best detective novel I have ever read. 2019~2024, five years witnessed huge change of HK and my views. Years ago I was treating protests with Game Theory, now what?</p></li><li><p><strong>Down and Out in Paris and London</strong> by <em>George Orwell</em>. I love people’s adventure in 1910s to 1930s, somehow exactly 100 years ago. I feel that their experience would serve as a reference to my future adventures in 2020s. In 2023 my family was half joking about me possibly being in a “down and out” stage, but whatever experienced by Orwell was beyond imaginable. The closest example to me is LC, but he is choosing that lifestyle, not forced by serious issues.</p></li></ul><h3 id="End"><a href="#End" class="headerlink" title="End"></a>End</h3><p>A few pages on bridge, probably too few so that my declaring was disastrous in Atlanta…</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Books</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Eat, Cook, Love</title>
    <link href="/2025/01/05/Eat-Cook-Love/"/>
    <url>/2025/01/05/Eat-Cook-Love/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Cook"><a href="#Cook" class="headerlink" title="Cook"></a>Cook</h2><p>During <strong>summer 2018</strong>, my parents gave an intensive cooking training to be prepared for my new life abroad. Just some basics, stir-fry some vegetables, eggs and tomatoes, pork and green peppers, eggplants, fried shrimps, etc.</p><p>I was confident that I gonna cook my own meals for the whole college years, until the first weekend, I got the wrong pot and triggered the <strong>fire alarm</strong>. It has something to do with my “training” conditions, as back in our apartment in Beijing, we had to turn on the stove with the help of a lighter and I was told to get used to the startling blasts of heated oil and vapor.</p><p>That marked my long habit of eating in <strong><em>Mensa</em></strong> and by <strong><em>Just Eat</em></strong>. I had made limited amount of properly self cooked meals. Other than those, it was usually instant <strong><em>Shin-Ramyun</em></strong> noodle with egg, or <strong><em>Barilla</em></strong> with bottled Ragù sauce.</p><p>Afraid to set off the alarm again was one reason, the other one was laziness. It took too long to slice a <strong><em>carrota</em></strong> to the perfect thinness I desire.</p><p>The “habit” was carried on in Leuven, where I got takeout from a Hunanese shop whose owners were from <strong><em>识字岭</em></strong> 80% of time, and in Ann Arbor during my first half there, where I explored <strong><em>FanTuan</em></strong> and then mocked in the group chat about alleged undergrads stealing takeouts in front of <strong><em>Munger</em></strong>.</p><p>Thing got changed in the second half of <strong><em>2023</em></strong>.</p><p>First I have to say that eating takeouts&#x2F;deliveries is a quite costly habit. My roommates in Leuven asked multiple times <strong><em>“How could you afford eating takeouts so frequently?”</em></strong>. I was under the illusion that the difference was not that great, and I was also being “comforted” that “it’s the pandemic, there’s nothing wrong eating something nice.” Upon reflection, a bunch of college roommates <strong>without much savings</strong>, living in shared <strong>small apartments</strong> on <strong>stipends</strong>, eating home-made meals from <strong>budget supermarkets</strong>, rotating <strong>old clothes</strong>, going everywhere on <strong>second-hand bikes</strong>, having a <strong>part time job</strong> as a delivery guy… that’s the kind of Utopian youthful life that I somehow admire.</p><p>Back to my reality. Being at the lowest point and spending time again in Beijing, I picked up my cooking skills and improved on it. Taste and efficiency are the two pillar stones, and I motivated myself to look for suitable ingredients. Mom helped a lot in this. She believes that picking up the pot and turning on the stove are key steps for me to get back to the game. And I did. Lots of things in my life are like cooking a simple meal for me: I know how to do it, yet I just need to motivate myself.</p><p>Therefore, the year <strong><em>2024</em></strong> was the year I had about 95% of meals at home. Ordering is now an option that is both expensive and time-consuming, as I would usually spend less than 30 minutes cooking my dinner and next day lunch (usually pork belly stir-fried with green pepper and cilantro, plus cabbage, or eggs and tomato). Stirring the spatula is now a swift adept yet enjoyable relaxing process.</p><h2 id="Eat"><a href="#Eat" class="headerlink" title="Eat"></a>Eat</h2><p>I should have started enjoying cooking way much earlier, based on my changes in eating and weights.</p><p>Growing up, I was sometimes picky on certain food, and often described as “eating too little”. Things like seaweed soup were nightmares for me when we just moved to Beijing. I had a generally “passive” attitude towards delicacies, when asked about “what’s my favorite”, I had the standard answer of <em>米粉</em> and <em>四季豆</em>.</p><p>After all, my parents are enthusiastic food lovers. I guess my appreciation have been growing since later high school. Partly thanks to the HNSDFZ <strong>alumni</strong> <em>“eat, drink, play, fun”</em> group, I enjoy all the times we explore the hidden gems of different cuisine, and took them as a part of awaking of self-identity, trying to appreciate all the details of my origin culture. One key moment I remember was during our graduation trip in <strong><em>ChengDU</em></strong>, where I realized that I could handle and genuinely enjoy the spicy hotpot and the Garlic Oil Dipping Sauce, which I <em>never</em> did in any occasion before. Also, in general, noticing what sauce and ingredient were used, pondering what were the techniques and tricks, those stuff become fun. I had not noticed that I was noticing those stuff until my dad pointed it out some point in <strong>2019</strong>.</p><p>Diversity in eating and cooking habits is also a fun stuff to pay attention to. I remember a small quarrel between me and MS during a school trip on <strong>“is it ok to put vegetables in hotpot at an early stage of the meal”</strong>, and another interesting conversation about <strong>should we peel the tomatoes before cooking</strong> with YD.</p><h2 id="Love"><a href="#Love" class="headerlink" title="Love"></a>Love</h2><p>Why do I want to mention food and cooking at the dawn of <strong>2025</strong>? Partially because of the background (a fantastic Bridge tournament despite our results, accompanied by lovely teammates and bridge players), the three dinners at <a href="https://thesparrowatl.com/">The Sparrow</a> were beyond enjoyable as I remember. I would describe the food there <strong>diverse, authentic, with reasonable price, and appealing to everyone whether you are from Chinese descent or not.</strong> Remember, I am now at a stage when I almost always prefer meals cooked by myself than restaurants.</p><p>To be fair, I probably cannot make a objective comment to that place, but hey, that’s the point, isn’t? Enjoy lovely meals with people of <strong><em>love and passion</em></strong>.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Self-Mumbling</category>
      
      <category>Food</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>It&#39;s My Party?</title>
    <link href="/2024/11/20/It-s-My-Party/"/>
    <url>/2024/11/20/It-s-My-Party/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It is quite impossible now to assess what <strong>Tat Ming Pair</strong>, <strong>Wong Yiu Ming</strong>, and <strong>Chow Yiu Fai</strong> meant to me <em>before September 2019</em>. I would always think about them with bias generated in next few years. Without those memories, where would Tat Ming stand in my heart?</p><h1 id="Music-and-Society-Episode-6"><a href="#Music-and-Society-Episode-6" class="headerlink" title="Music and Society, Episode 6"></a>Music and Society, Episode 6</h1><h3 id="Stories-with-Tat-Ming-Pair"><a href="#Stories-with-Tat-Ming-Pair" class="headerlink" title="Stories with Tat Ming Pair"></a>Stories with Tat Ming Pair</h3><p><strong>On that Mid-Autumn day in 2019</strong>, it simply occurred to me that Tat Ming had some truly culturally Chinese songs, and their styles and choice of instruments reflected a unique vibe combined with traditional art and modern values. So, after a few traditional songs, <strong>Teresa Teng</strong>, <strong>Qi Qin</strong>, <strong>Faye Wang</strong>, etc… It became their party, Tat and Ming.</p><p>The rest were magic, destiny, or whatever you want to call.</p><p>At that time, a few close friends of mine would primarily label my music taste with <strong>Lo Tayu</strong> and <strong>Alan Tam</strong>. I would mostly agree too. My <strong>TuiGe</strong> statistics gathered in April 2020 showed that my top 7 singers, apart from those two, were: <strong>Eason Chen</strong>, <strong>Faye Wang</strong>, <strong>Leslie Cheung</strong>, <strong>Tat Ming Pair</strong>, and <strong>Karen Mok</strong>.</p><p>The styles and vibes were the first reasons I started to like Tat Ming. Hearing <strong>石头记</strong> for the first time on radio <strong>97.4</strong> during <strong>Wang Dong</strong>‘s programme, my father introduced them to me, and shared his opinion of them being quite representative as cultural and ethnic musicians. <strong>石头记</strong> was also the first song of them that connected me with others. In the early <em>TuiGe</em> days, <strong>Song Gong</strong> (<em>mate, hope you are doing well</em>) told me that it was one of his favorite songs.</p><p>Then, <em>TuiGe</em> demanded me to explore more “less popular” music, and that was the time I began to gain more comprehensive pictures of the musicians I like. Tat Ming, in particular, served as a source of <strong>uniqueness</strong>. Their focus on some <strong>minorities</strong> topics and novelty were quite useful when I needed a surprise song to impress.</p><p>For example, <strong>你还爱我吗</strong> was the first attempt to imply romantic relationship to a girl. <strong>寂寞的人有福了</strong> kind of reflected my mindset in the autumn of 2015.</p><p>Other than those, I could not think of anything too special to me in case of Tat Ming. I did not even care too much of <strong>Chow Yiu Fai</strong> during that time, when <em>you</em> were listening to his talk in person, I was skipping Chemistry exam to see <strong>Stomp</strong> performing in our school.</p><p><strong>Entering adulthood</strong>, politics became a key factor in my music listening. Tat Ming, along with <strong>Bobby Chen</strong> and <strong>Li Zhi</strong>, therefore, elevated on my all time list. I appreciated what they expressed in songs, and how somehow they did not compromise their opinions for profits.</p><p>Pre 2019 September, I was listening to their 30-year anniversary song in June. Apart from that, musicians like them are super good at producing songs that appeal to the whole society with some “Melancholic Hope”, like their <strong>今天世上所有地方</strong>, and <strong>Lo Tayu</strong>‘s <strong>伴侣</strong> (both 2004 and 2020 versions). They preserved some serious <strong>collective memory</strong> of our society with great <strong>empathy</strong>, and guided us to some universal hope.</p><p>So, that’s what Tat Ming meant to me before I met <em>you</em>. I had to confess that some of the songs only became familiar to me afterwards, like <strong>皇后大盗</strong>, <strong>四季交易会</strong>, <strong>口吃</strong>. Nonetheless, the originally already specialness of Tat Ming, with what happened to us, reached a level of <strong>utmost specialness</strong>. In case of <strong>今夜星光灿烂</strong>, the worry of late-20th-century Hong Kong in transition, is intwined with the sorrow of covid distanced love, I still treasure every moment of it.</p><p><strong>Now, fast forward to 2024 October.</strong></p><p>It’s hard to say my mindset when I suddenly decided to go to <strong>Anthony Wong Yiu Ming</strong>‘s concert when offered free tickets. Before the trip, I was not sure if it would be reactivating those post-2019 memory, or it would be a way to say hello to an even younger version of myself.</p><p>Sense told me, that, if carrying too much <strong>emotions attached</strong> from the past, the journey would be disappointing. I had placed too many symbols and meanings that are only personal but not quite applicable in reality. The most meanings and happiness were given to me by Tat Ming in presence of those specific background and people, not by the person, Wong, or Lau.</p><p>So, compared to those “truer” fans I met in Vancouver, I did not enjoy the concert as much as they did, but I still had quite a journey of self-exploring. Back in that therapy group, I called that a trip of <strong>Desensitization</strong>. It was an adventure that helped me <strong>relocate</strong> Tat Ming and Wong back to the position of <strong>“one of the musicians I love”</strong> from “something utterly special”.</p><p>That being said, I have seen clearly how I am different from people who see Wong as their <strong>“favorite without doubt”</strong>, and I kind of successfully <strong>separated</strong> “what I like about Tat Ming’s songs”, “what I appreciate Wong as a person”, and “what I cherish from my days with <em>you</em>“.</p><p>Eventually, I would not need to ask the question, <strong>“is it my party?”</strong>. I now know more clearly where the lines are.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Music and Society</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Ding Junhui&#39;s First Ranking Title in Five Years</title>
    <link href="/2024/11/10/Ding-Junhui-s-First-Ranking-Title-in-Five-Years/"/>
    <url>/2024/11/10/Ding-Junhui-s-First-Ranking-Title-in-Five-Years/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h4 id="I-love-writing-sports-news-so-here-we-go"><a href="#I-love-writing-sports-news-so-here-we-go" class="headerlink" title="I love writing sports news, so here we go:"></a>I love writing sports news, so here we go:</h4><h1 id="Ding-Junhui-Won-His-First-Ranking-Title-in-Five-Years"><a href="#Ding-Junhui-Won-His-First-Ranking-Title-in-Five-Years" class="headerlink" title="Ding Junhui Won His First Ranking Title in Five Years"></a>Ding Junhui Won His First Ranking Title in Five Years</h1><p>Oct 10th 2024, <strong>Nanjing</strong>, Jiangsu, China. Chinese legend <strong>Ding Junhui</strong> beat English player <strong>Chris Wakelin</strong> by 10-7 to win the 2024 World Snooker Tour <strong>International Championship</strong>.</p><p>Wakelin had a good start, leading Ding by 4-1, but the “<strong>Dragon</strong>“ recovered swiftly, established a lead of 5-4 when the first session ended. He later extended his lead by 7-4, while Wakelin chased back to 7-6. Ding then claimed 3 of last 4 frames to win <strong>10-7</strong> comfortably.</p><p>Both players showed great form in the final. Wakelin compiled 6 half-centuries while Ding knocked 8 half-centuries.</p><p>It is the “Dragon”‘s <strong>15th</strong> ranking event title of his career and the first one in nearly 5 years. His last one was the <strong>UK Championship in Dec 2019</strong>. With three lost finals in past two year, it’s one of the longest ranking title draught periods for Ding’s career, he celebrated with a fist pump when potting the winning black, and the Chinese crowd roared with great excitement to congratulate his victory. In the post-match interview, he specially thanked the fans who kept supporting him in those tough year, <strong><em>“It was a tough time not just for me but for my fans, we had to suffer a lot these years, and I’m glad we all made it through.”</em></strong></p><p>With this victory, Ding claimed 175000 pounds for prize money and ranking points, making him back to the <strong>top-8</strong> of the ranking list, and a last-minute spot for the Champion of Champions next week held in Bolton. Wakelin, with 75000 pounds gained, raised his ranking to <strong>top-16</strong> for the first time in his career.</p><h4 id="Now-personal"><a href="#Now-personal" class="headerlink" title="Now, personal:"></a>Now, personal:</h4><p>Ding is always a <strong>childhood hero</strong> for me. Thanks to my father, I grew my interests in all kinds of sports at a quite young age. Fortunately, during my elementary and middle school years, China had witnessed a huge spurt of world-class athletes in many sports. I could never forget cheering in front of the television for the victory moments of <strong><em>Ding Junhui, Li Na, Yao Ming, Liu Xiang</em></strong>, etc… and feeling extremely sad during those lost matches. Even though I did not fully understand the rules of some of the games, those athletes and sport teams served as an early <strong>patriotic</strong> lessons, and their stories were so <strong>inspiring and motivational</strong> that they helped me a lot for my life and especially bridge competitions.</p><p>Growing up a little bit, when I reached 14 or 15, my focus kind of switched to football completely, rooting for Milan every weekend (stress on the <strong><em>WEEKEND</em></strong>, as we had no UCL games during that time), which was a little bit self torturing and depressing.</p><p>I vaguely remember the 2016 WC final, when <strong>Ding lost 14-18 to Selby</strong>. Me and my father did not follow it closely as the game was mostly in midnight, but the memory of the joy hearing that Ding reached final and the sadness of both Ding and Marco Fu losing to Selby are still vivid.</p><p>Ding’s last victory in UK 2019 is also an exciting moment, but I only returned to closely following snooker later in 2022 after <strong>Zhao Xintong</strong>‘s UK victory. In short, lots of things changed because of <strong>Covid</strong>. When having to spend most of your time alone in bedroom. snooker seemed to be a great entertainment to watch peacefully.</p><p>Just like Ding’s winning momentum was halted by covid immediately after his Dec 2019 win, <strong>we all suffered in some levels when the pandemic stroke</strong>. Some impact was brief and recovered sooner, some impact was <strong>profound and it took a long patient period of waiting, self-searching, and re-grouping</strong>.</p><p>Personally, I take this five-year-waited victory of Ding as a <strong>symbol</strong> of those kinds of <strong>“long, patient, and somehow tormenting”</strong> resurrection period of post-covid life. I am grateful to have witnessed it today, and I keep telling myself not let those symbols dictate my feelings, just like how devastating I felt watching Ding’s lost to Allen in 2022 UK, lonely in a room crowded with happy faces watching Qatar World Cup opening game.</p><p>Best wishes to all.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Sports</category>
      
      <category>Snooker</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Arms Against Tyranny</title>
    <link href="/2024/09/28/Arms-Against-Tyranny/"/>
    <url>/2024/09/28/Arms-Against-Tyranny/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Just finished reading <a href="https://www.oupchina.com.hk/zh/general-interest/humanities/tyranny"><strong><em>BaoZhengShi</em></strong> by <strong><em>Xu Ben</em></strong></a>. Obviously it is not on Douban, so I am marking it here.</p><p>I seem to be bothered by this topic everyday, and reading it does not make things better. Other than seeing the same types of stories again and again, there’s nothing much you may do apart from remembering.</p><p>So let’s keep this at minimum amount, and talk about music. Title? It’s from a DLC of HOI4.</p><h1 id="Music-and-Society-Episode-5"><a href="#Music-and-Society-Episode-5" class="headerlink" title="Music and Society, Episode 5"></a>Music and Society, Episode 5</h1><p>I mentioned some songs of Taiwan in <a href="https://fredfreddo.github.io/2024/08/13/Green-Island/">Green Island</a>. The last one I wanted to say is <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iV8JDbtXZm4"><strong><em>Island’s Sunrise</em></strong></a> by <strong><em>Fire EX.</em></strong> The songs was composed to pay tribute to the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sunflower_Student_Movement"><strong><em>Sunflower Movement</em></strong></a>.</p><p>In the last few days, some people were commemorating the ten-year anniversary of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Umbrella_Movement"><strong><em>Umbrella Movement</em></strong></a> in HK. A notable song of that event is <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5swov1Zl_0k"><strong><em>Hold High Our Umbrellas</em></strong></a> written by <strong><em>Albert Leung</em>_</strong>.</p><p>There are many other examples. Songs were created specifically for some incident or mission, and they were sung by the crowd, and they became a classic or icon for the future.</p><p>Anyway, what I wanted to say is that there seems to be a significant gap of new&#x2F;contemporary songs of those kind on our side of the world. We do not lack incidents, we do not lack great musicians, but certain reasons prevent the stories and songs be known on a wider scale. Take that few decades ago as example, tons of songs were made to commemorate it afterwards, but no new song was made during that time that became popular enough, even though some great musicians were the front-line participators.</p><p>That feeling was strong during the covid years til the end of 2022. I have seen many songs sung during many occasions, but they were all old ones. Popular choices include “<strong><em>Do you hear the people sing</em></strong>“, <strong><em>Internationale</em></strong>, and multiple songs by <strong><em>Beyond</em></strong>. It could be the problem with the music industry or simply censorship, it’s been a while. We don’t even have any good ode songs.</p><p>Those songs have two types. One is what people may sing all together when gathering on the street or square: strong, rhythmic, straightforward lyrics. Those ones are responsible to become popular. The other is less popular, with more complex melody and lyrics. This type serves more artistic value.</p><p>Even tough we lack some first type, we had some great ones that belong to the second type during this century. I give one example here:</p><p>In the album <a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=OLAK5uy_lkjDUIKZzMKQUZ6fWfAh92dd9OLaFC_X0"><strong><em>Trip to Temple Fair II</em></strong></a> (2011) by <strong><em>Zuoxiao Zuzhou</em></strong>, there is a song about <a href="https://zh.wikipedia.org/wiki/%E9%92%B1%E4%BA%91%E4%BC%9A%E4%BA%8B%E4%BB%B6"><strong><em>Qian YunHui</em></strong></a>.</p><p>There’s a lot more. And thankfully people are still producing more, no matter if they are trendy and making tons from concerts, or if they are censored and whispering in their friendly gatherings.</p><p>I enjoy looking at that type of songs during that time. Each song has a tragedy behind, but each song successfully marks an unforgettable memory. When you look at most cases, the song and the incident represent a significant milestone of development of economy or justice in our society. It was the time when we discussed the death of a poor vendor at politics class, and things were seemingly being addressed and moving in the right direction.</p><p>I want more.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Music and Society</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Szczęsny and new semester</title>
    <link href="/2024/08/27/Szczesny-and-new-semester/"/>
    <url>/2024/08/27/Szczesny-and-new-semester/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Wojciech Szczęsny</strong> retired from professional football today.</p><p>I’m not a fan of him or Juventus. It just reminds me of some good old days, when our dear microeconomics professor Dr.Marengo used Szczęsny and then-Roma goalkeeper <strong>Olsen</strong> to demonstrate how basic <strong>Game Theory</strong> works when they kick penalties against each other. Because of him, I never know how to properly pronounce Szczęsny, and kept saying “Scesni”.</p><p>Looking back at those, I think that’s one of the main reasons I love the days studying in Roma. Another example? <strong>Andrea Pirlo’s free transfer</strong> was used to show how <strong>depreciation</strong> works in accounting.</p><p>Now, today.</p><p>This is the <strong>third</strong> time I witness the first week of school year at Ann Arbor. Terribly <strong>hot</strong> and changeable weather, chaotic bus schedule and tons of freshmen with their innocent bright young faces…</p><p>All the three times, I feel a little annoyed and envy by the scenes on campus, especially when I walked around in the <strong>Festifall</strong>. In 2021, I was quite excited on the Diag, checking out all fancy clubs and societies there. That when I did not see myself as a proper graduate student, but someone who’s trying to make up something that was missed from my own undergraduate years, which were short, having less social engagement, and interrupted by Covid. The same feeling comes again and again in the next years.</p><p>So, the standard saying would be, know what life stage you are now, know your missions and priorities. And some of your feelings are too emotional which would look unreasonable from other people’s perspectives.</p><p>On my 24th birthday, I joked that “I feel old”. Well, make some <strong>old and mature</strong> moves then.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Sports</category>
      
      <category>Football</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Green Island</title>
    <link href="/2024/08/13/Green-Island/"/>
    <url>/2024/08/13/Green-Island/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I am no literature critic, but experienced enough to taste the difference. Reflecting the suffering and history of a nation by stories of ordinary people, some become epic, some fall into cliche. Nonetheless, it is always appalling to see how similar the tragedies were.</p><p>The book I am talking about is <em>Green Island</em> by <strong>Shawna Yang</strong>. I like the story, that kind of novels is quite needed. It was a pity that the focus moved away from the island during the last part, and I’d hope to find another story based on that period. It almost feels like that you endured the tragedy, fought the tragedy, yet you did not paint the future with bright colors. Also, the gender division at the revolutionary front was nearly reactionary.</p><p>Casting all those aside, let’s talk about music, the music that accompanied the fights and sufferings of some lovely people.</p><h1 id="Music-and-Society-Episode-4"><a href="#Music-and-Society-Episode-4" class="headerlink" title="Music and Society, Episode 4"></a>Music and Society, Episode 4</h1><h2 id="Green-Island"><a href="#Green-Island" class="headerlink" title="Green Island"></a>Green Island</h2><p>The title <em>Green Island</em> is from one of the most famous song of that time, <strong><em>The Green Island Serenade</em></strong>. Reportedly the song was originally romantic, while the “Green” simply referring to the beauty of the greater island. Over the years, people cannot help but associate the name with the Green Island located alone in the Pacific, originally “Island of Fire”, where the <em>White Terror</em> used to place all sorts of prisoners. It has the vibe, you have to admit: <strong>“The night in Green Island is so dark and intoxicating, dear girl, why are you still as silent as a clam, not confiding to me?”</strong> Love songs and political innuendos are always inseparable, aren’t they?</p><h2 id="Formosa-“Mei-Li-Dao”"><a href="#Formosa-“Mei-Li-Dao”" class="headerlink" title="Formosa “Mei Li Dao”"></a>Formosa “Mei Li Dao”</h2><p>The <em>“Coke Can Incident”</em> of Li Shuangze at Tamkang University was a beautiful story. It got everything, courage, enlightenment, independence, dignity, mercurial talent, and tragedy. The later political movements originated from the magazine with same name changed everything. The book, unfortunately, did not write too much on that, focusing on the fear during the eve of the incidents, while not saying anything on the outcome.</p><p>The song, like others, are exploited with kinds of interpretation and usage. Generally it’s loved by all, a great representation and praise to the Island. Interestingly, it could be played on a 520 day, and my favorite version is performed by <strong>Parangalan</strong>, who appeared frequently on CCTV shows in the past decade.</p><h2 id="The-Orphan-of-Asia"><a href="#The-Orphan-of-Asia" class="headerlink" title="The Orphan of Asia"></a>The Orphan of Asia</h2><p><em><strong>Yellow faced tainted by Red dirts, Black eyeballs filled with White terror</strong></em>.</p><p>There were striking similarities, but I guess one side goes way further in the degree of cruelness and magic realism…</p><h2 id="more"><a href="#more" class="headerlink" title="(more)"></a>(more)</h2><p>There’s more, some even composed and designated specifically to some events, let’s put them into another episode. One might say that it is quite unusual that there is no notable songs made popular enough during THAT YEAR, given figures like Hou actually being there.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Music and Society</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Italia Eliminata</title>
    <link href="/2024/06/29/Italia-Eliminata/"/>
    <url>/2024/06/29/Italia-Eliminata/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Surprise"><a href="#Surprise" class="headerlink" title="Surprise"></a>Surprise</h2><p>I was a little bit surprised to see <strong>El Shaarawy</strong> in the line-up. In the last 20 minutes of the game against <strong>Croatia</strong>, when <strong>Spalletti</strong> chose to send in <strong>Zaccagni</strong> instead of Stephan, I thought that was the end for him, finally getting the chance to represent the country yet making no appearance. Spalletti’s decision turned out to be perfect, as Zaccagni saved the day, but it did not prevent the delayed humiliation today.</p><h2 id="Twelve-Years"><a href="#Twelve-Years" class="headerlink" title="Twelve Years"></a>Twelve Years</h2><p>There’s a <em>meme</em> online when Shaarawy was called for EURO.</p><p><a href="https://www.instagram.com/thefootballarena/p/C8Oz-uepF0q/"><img src="/images/images.jfif" alt="Stephan El Shaarawy: 2012 and 2024"></a></p><p>On the left was the young <strong>“Il Faraone”</strong> that I fell in love with when I first started following football seriously. Sadly, he did not achieve what was expected to a “Golden Boy”. During those year, him, Milan, and probably us, all had our ups and downs. In 12 years, one turns into a neatly-groomed experienced man from the young cocky wonderkid with the <strong>Mohican</strong> haircut.</p><h2 id="Career"><a href="#Career" class="headerlink" title="Career"></a>Career</h2><p>Shaarawy leaving <strong>Milan</strong> was one of the saddest things I felt in my middle school years. His career was quite plain after that. Having settled in <strong>Roma</strong> for years, he finally became a veteran of the eternal city, and no one will ever expect him to be a Milan legend one day. The nickname, Il Faraone, given by his being part-Egyptian, was forgot and later gloriously sticked on the true Egyptian star, once his teammates in Roma, <strong>Mo Salah</strong>. Interestingly, Shaarawy did consider representing Egypt instead of Italia: two Pharaohs on the wings, just imagine that.</p><p>He only got three professional trophies in his career so far, and surprisingly two of them are in China: the <strong>Supercoppa</strong> with Milan won in <strong>Beijing</strong>, and the Chinese <strong>FA Cup</strong> during his short spell with <strong>Shanghai Shenhua</strong>.</p><h2 id="EURO-2020-e-2024"><a href="#EURO-2020-e-2024" class="headerlink" title="EURO 2020 e 2024"></a>EURO 2020 e 2024</h2><p>Anyway, back to Italia. Many would say that the victory three years ago at <strong>EURO 2020</strong> was just a irregularity of this extremely mediocre team in the past decade. <strong>Mancini</strong> performed the wonder, and could not hold it any longer. Downgrade in the center backs (no BBC anymore, if <strong>Acerbi</strong> was available today, that would have made a difference), terrible wing backs (as a Milan fan, I am so confused that why <strong>Calabria</strong> is so consistently left out by the coach), Scudetto-winning midfield yet without no true playmaker, and sub-bar attacking line (only <strong>Chiesa</strong> doing something, and sadly <strong>Berardi</strong> is absent).</p><p>Nonetheless, I enjoy and truly miss the <strong>summer of 2021</strong>, watching the passionate <strong>Azzurri</strong> fighting. Those nights in Roma, with the large screen in <em>Viale Pola</em>, with the classmates and professors shouting <strong>L’Inno di Mameli</strong>, with friends in Latin America, with her…</p><p>The glory, the joy, the pride of wonderkids, all <em>long gone</em>. Let’s treasure those memories, and try to <strong>bring some more, shall we?</strong></p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Sports</category>
      
      <category>Football</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Yellow Faces</title>
    <link href="/2024/05/31/Yellow-Faces/"/>
    <url>/2024/05/31/Yellow-Faces/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="Music-and-Society-Episode-3"><a href="#Music-and-Society-Episode-3" class="headerlink" title="Music and Society, Episode 3"></a>Music and Society, Episode 3</h1><p>I came across a little collection of <strong>Chow Yiu-fai</strong>‘s essays a few weeks ago at the library.</p><p>Partly due to my nostalgic obsession, partly due to the regret of not having read that “unicorn” book, I enjoyed most of the materials. I strongly related to what I had already heard or been aware of, and quickly skipped those with remote connections. It explored the identity of being Chinese in modern pop music. One interesting part is that it made the assumption that the <strong>“Zhongguofeng”</strong> music in Taiwan appeared more <strong><em>masculine</em></strong>, while those in Hong Kong seemed to have more <strong><em>feminine</em></strong> touch.</p><p>What I want to focus today is the story of the song <strong>“黄种人”</strong> mentioned in the book. I had never seriously listened to that song before, as I loathed the seemingly <em>“Koushui”</em> title and I was <em>reluctant</em> to use Yellow to represent all Chinese people. Like what <strong>Hou Dejian</strong>, who wrote <strong>“龙的传人”</strong>, said in a concert during that tumultuous year: “I used to believe that black eyes, black hair, and yellow faces could represent Chinese people, but I realized that I was wrong when I met <strong>xxxx</strong>, he reminded me that not all Chinese people looked like that, so I changed the lyrics to ‘no matter you wish it or not, we are forever the heirs of Loong.’”.</p><p>I checked the comment area and bullet screen of the song in multiple platforms. Apparently, it is a quite <strong>inspiring and uplifting</strong> song made during the time of that early wave of <strong>patriotism</strong> in the first years of 21st century. There was hardly any talk of the lyrics writer Chow and his motive of composition. He admitted that he <strong>intentionally avoided</strong> using the word “Chinese” and chose “Yellow” for several reasons:</p><ul><li>The concept of being “Chinese” was <strong>deeply abused</strong> and kind of monopolized by the mainstream</li><li>He was concerned about the <strong>xenophobic tendency</strong> appeared in other so-called “patriotic” songs</li><li>Discussing Chinese identity in his terms may have some potential issue with the <strong>censorship</strong> bureau</li><li>He then tried to add some <strong>innuendo of barbaric monarchs and internal conflicts</strong></li><li>He also <strong>avoid using “we”</strong>, and <strong>insisted on using “I”</strong> to emphasize the individualism he treasured</li></ul><p>It was a mind-blowing experience reading that part, even though I could claim that I love and know Chow’s work well. The contrast of his intention and the fans’ reaction I witnessed was so striking that I felt a little sadness when looking at people saying how proud they are singing this song, thinking the lessons of all the historical tragedies Chow tried to express.</p><p>Back to Yellow. Based on what Hou said, I developed a sense of <strong>exploring the diversity in China</strong>. Probably partially due to me being exposed to the western cultures and values, I genuinely believe the power of diversity, and I keep trying to establish that China actually has a stronger diversity than any other western societies. Geography, culture, language, cuisine, you name it. Every Chinese shall proudly express their unique sub-identities as a part of being Chinese, and that will help make us confident and stronger.</p><p>With less room to explore those identities, it is not surprising to see how the senses of confusion and being lost arose in certain groups of people, and how they are expressing themselves by music in a tactful way.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Music and Society</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>They Summoned the Summer</title>
    <link href="/2024/05/12/They-Summoned-the-Summer/"/>
    <url>/2024/05/12/They-Summoned-the-Summer/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>“It’s hot in here, it must be <strong>Summer</strong>“</p><p>Gladly, AA is not that hot during summer months. A day could be pleasantly spent with cool breezes and not-so-strong sunshine, although some flies and mosquitos could be a bit annoying.</p><p>It’s been more than a month since last time. Things went quite okay, and I am trying to embrace this brand new summer.</p><h1 id="Music-and-Society-Episode-2"><a href="#Music-and-Society-Episode-2" class="headerlink" title="Music and Society, Episode 2"></a>Music and Society, Episode 2</h1><p>I chose a not so radical topic for the first article, as genuinely, and ideally, we actually do not need that much outcry.</p><p>Sometime during high school, I was imagining what songs should be chosen if the topics are <strong><em>four seasons</em></strong>. <strong>“他夏了夏天”</strong> by <strong>SodaGreen</strong> is a special one for summer.</p><p>I love <strong>QingFeng</strong>‘s voice since long time ago. The most impressive one was his cover of <strong>“我只在乎你”</strong>. For a young school kid, I could not feel any of what Teresa Teng did to men of <em>older</em> generations, but I could totally relate with Wu. He has one of the cleanest voices, and he expressed the emotions with some <strong>‘vulnerable strength’</strong>, with a bit of naivety. Interestingly, I do not like Zhou Shen, although I am not sure if they should be comparable.</p><p>I generally appreciate singers showing characteristics which are <strong>traditionally labeled with the opposite gender</strong>, and it’s actually quite common. Vulnerability, anger, sassiness and confidence. Some mixture of those certainly make things fun.</p><p>Back to topic.</p><p>I only realized the sense of <strong>social responsibility</strong> of SodaGreen when I was in college. I was going through their Winter songs on Youtube during those sleepless nights on <em>Via Lisbona</em>. For a long time I would say their work expressed exactly that ‘lightness’ of the so-called <strong>‘Petite bourgeoisie’</strong>, with those closeness to the nature and some weird imaginations, but that day I came to know for the first time of their songs with caring for the society. Their love and respect for <strong>minorities</strong>, their recognizing culture and art…</p><p>For this song, I took the liberty to modified a bit into English. On a road trip one day in October, while me and J singing it together, I believed that it is the best song, <strong>better than any “red” songs</strong>, to be used by the state machine to <strong>celebrate the working class</strong>. With a simple narrative of a normal workday, it contains the challenges and tiredness of the work, but expressed in an optimistic and upbeat tones, which probably coincide with what we were told to work hard happily even though the overall situation may be bad…</p><p>“In the sweet burden, he finds his greatest solace.”</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Music and Society</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Spring Returns to Earth</title>
    <link href="/2024/04/07/Spring-Returns-to-Earth/"/>
    <url>/2024/04/07/Spring-Returns-to-Earth/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="Music-and-Society-Episode-1"><a href="#Music-and-Society-Episode-1" class="headerlink" title="Music and Society, Episode 1"></a>Music and Society, Episode 1</h1><p>One may assume I would talk about protest or politics music, but let’s start with some more <strong>universal humane emotions</strong>.</p><p>Spring, seasons.</p><p>We welcome spring back to the town. Red blossoms on the trees, sun pushes away those heavy coats, people jumping on the grass, high, or shy…</p><p>Interestingly I first heard this song from <strong>Kaiserreich</strong> BGM. They did a terrific job on selecting appropriate songs for different countries and scenarios. Apart from the good tastes of those mod creators, the key is that we got so many brilliant ballads, marches, early pop… In China, you may have been hearing the voices of those unforgettable singers hundred years ago.</p><p>There’s the seductive vibes of those who lost in <strong>Shanghai’s material luxury</strong>; there’s the desperate cries of lowly errand boys; there’s heroic charge against the imperial oppression; there’s bitter-sweet celebration of the aftermath…No matter which alternate universe we were in, those expressions of universal emotions in the early days of widely-spread and recorded songs would perfectly fit in.</p><p><strong>大地回春, Spring returns to Earth</strong>. It was a few weeks ago when we appreciated some performances of fellow students in the name of “Taste of Taiwan”. “A song to celebrate the spring,” as the host of that classical music team said. Perhaps the most popular example in this context is <strong>恭喜恭喜</strong>, whose more jubilant version is still ubiquitous in all places during the Spring Festival time, and is widely-taught online to be the typical song of a mixture of sorrow and joy, written to commemorate the <strong>Pyrrhic victory in the war of resistance against imperial Japan</strong>. Spring returns to Earth, also a song in the post-war era (probably released in Hong Kong), somehow expressed the similar sadness but mostly hope and resilience for a unpredictable future.</p><p>It’s about neither cliches like love and sex, nor vigorous and spectacular crying for justice. There are songs that were luckily born in those eras, and brilliantly yet calmly expressed some common characteristics of a nation, stored these “shared memories in history” with vibrations that will be carried on eternally…</p><p>“Birds are singing endlessly, everything on the earth are happy to embrace a fresh start, hey!”</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Music and Society</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Clean the Blackboard</title>
    <link href="/2024/03/28/Clean-the-Blackboard/"/>
    <url>/2024/03/28/Clean-the-Blackboard/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I guess we have to postpone the “Music and Society” topic for a few days. (perhaps it is worth making that topic into series).</p><p>Anyway, I am somehow obsessive in keeping certain things tidy, clean, and organized. Such as phone scree, laptop.</p><p>From time to time when I use napkins, wet wipes, or lens cloth to clean my monitor, I’d remember the days in school watching fellow classmates cleaning blackboard in the classroom. In my memory, Z is the person who was the best in this task. It was satisfying seeing Z hovering along the platform, mastering the cloth in well-planned route on the surface again and again, leaving a bright clean blackboard without stain. I once asked about the method she used, and what’s the trick to leave no stain on the board. I hope this was not a weird feeling, as I myself like to clean things in the same way sometimes and I consider doing it as a refreshing and peaceful procedure. We do those things repeatedly, and people may view it as redundant work. Sometime the board was cleaned by brushing several times after the cloth, and the classes were starting in a few hours. “What’s the point?” they would ask.</p><p>Another major figure who did cleaning dedicatedly, devotedly, and thoroughly was H. The typical term we used to describe was “the spirit of sacrifice.” It was supposed to be a praise, but I felt judgemental every time hearing it. It was kind of formalist when I was the person doing the task. I remember a time when I was wringing the mop cloth with my hands, and D was by the side watching it, probably made a few comments. In that situation, cleaning in a dedicated manner was a demonstration of complaint, rebel, and perhaps protest. It was reaching an inner-reconciliation by extravagantly performing an basic task.</p><p>These were my views on cleaning under those circumstances. I do not know but am curious on how the people I mentioned think about when they were, or, are, doing these kinds of tasks. Perhaps there were some senses of feeling ignored and neglected? I have not realized the existence of that in those years until recently. Perhaps it was all about something that make yourself in peace? I am totally in favor. However, the truth is probably always a mixture of weird and inexpressible sentiments.</p><p>I constantly wipe away those white little dust on my laptop keyboard with my finger.</p><p>I just did.</p><p>Good night.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Self-Mumbling</category>
      
      <category>Random Thoughts</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>&#39;Occupy&#39;</title>
    <link href="/2024/03/20/Occupy/"/>
    <url>/2024/03/20/Occupy/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I listened to a book talk the other day. The topic is sensitive so I probably should now speak bluntly. Just that famous integer power of a prime number.</p><p>An Interesting joke made by the professor is that, “it was Chinese students who invented ‘Occupy’.”</p><p>The sentence seemed to come with a bit of pride and a bit of pity.</p><p>Also there were some other theories about triangles and games.</p><p>I of course is not a scholar in the field, so that was simply a way of reliving some inner struggle and pressure.</p><p>But hey, those topics, related to songs, then reminded me of relationships,…</p><p>Next articles would be about music and social responsibility and movements, I hope.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Self-Mumbling</category>
      
      <category>Random Thoughts</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Toledo</title>
    <link href="/2024/03/01/Toledo/"/>
    <url>/2024/03/01/Toledo/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>What do you think of when you hear the word “Toledo”?</p><p>First of all, it may depend on the pronunciation. People in America would pronounce it as [təˈlidoʊ] (with a short ‘i’ like in ‘hit’), while many would say [toleðo] (same quick speed but with ‘e’ as in ‘made’). Or, perhaps a even weirder one as [tolˈeːðoː] (with a long stressed dutch ‘ee’). You may try listening to the pronunciations by copying the symbols <a href="http://ipa-reader.xyz/">here</a>. Male American English, Castilian Spanish, and Male Dutch are recommended as readers.</p><h2 id="The-American-Toledo"><a href="#The-American-Toledo" class="headerlink" title="The American Toledo"></a>The American Toledo</h2><p>It is just a hour drive away from me, a small city located on the south side of the Michigan-Ohio border, where Maumee River runs into Lake Erie. It was a disputed area between Michigan and Ohio about two hundred years ago, when Michigan was about to become a state of the US. Two states nearly went into bloody war as Michigan finally compromised to hand over Toledo to Ohio in exchange for the recognition of the Upper Peninsula.</p><h2 id="The-Original-Toledo-de-la-Mancha"><a href="#The-Original-Toledo-de-la-Mancha" class="headerlink" title="The Original Toledo de la Mancha"></a>The Original Toledo de la Mancha</h2><p>Like half of the American names, Toledo of Ohio has its European Origin, Spain. From my limited history knowledge gained by playing Europa Universalis IV, Toledo was the political center of Kingdom of Castile until late 16th century when Ferdinand II brought the empire to its peak at Madrid.</p><p>The importance of the city Toledo thus explains why it is used to name cities in many American regions. Apart from Ohio, there are many other cities named after Toledo in the US and in Mexico, Uruguay…</p><p>The aristocratic family, de Toledo, is also derived from the reconquer of Toledo by the kingdom of León. One notable figure is the “Iron Duke” Fernando Álvarez de Toledo, who notoriously served as the Governor of Habsburg Netherlands during the early time of the eighty-year Dutch Revolt, which leads to our third meaning of Toledo:</p><h2 id="The-Common-Virtual-Learning-Environment-of-the-KU-Leuven-Association-since-2001"><a href="#The-Common-Virtual-Learning-Environment-of-the-KU-Leuven-Association-since-2001" class="headerlink" title="The Common Virtual Learning Environment of the KU Leuven Association (since 2001)"></a>The Common Virtual Learning Environment of the KU Leuven Association (since 2001)</h2><p>For many students in US, let’s say Toledo it’s the Belgian counterpart of ‘Canvas’.</p><p>My experience with Toledo platform was not that perfect during those exchange days. Too many bugs drove you crazy in the lockdown era. As I mentioned, my interest in history only grew after I left the continent, so, at that time I simply thought it is a funny name pronounced with a dramatic Flemish ‘e’, even though a friend learning Linguistics from Spain mentioned a bit on the city. Thinking back, I did notice some names and locations with strong Habsburg Spanish ties in Leuven, such as schools and churches.</p><p>It may be surprising that a Flemish Institution opt to name its online platform after a name with colonial and imperial implications. Perhaps they were not as rebellious as their compatriots in the north.</p><p>Anyway, I feel happy that I may link the name Toledo with some world history and my life stories. A year ago I was planning to a trip to Toledo Ohio but decided to cancel as I thought there was nothing special to see with relatively expensive trip cost.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Self-Mumbling</category>
      
      <category>Fun Fact</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Day Dream 1</title>
    <link href="/2024/02/20/Day-Dream-1/"/>
    <url>/2024/02/20/Day-Dream-1/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In the end, who is in charge of that chain?</p><p>I had a day dream the other day.</p><p>A little town in her lonely days. I was on the street towards south. The was a store for sausage on the left, and an apartment building on the right. That street appeared in my dream many time before. The background was a mixture of Leuven and what I imagined a small university town would be like.</p><p>I don’t remember if I was alone or with someone, but we were looking for grocery store.</p><p>There was one. Typical one, the one my friends talked about all the time yet I never visited even though it was a lot cheaper than the closer one I usually frequent.</p><p>It was quite empty, nothing special. Actually, no food, no grocery.</p><p>It felt happy, to be honest, with a bit a sense of helplessness, though.</p><p>A seemingly familiar environment, yet no strings attached, no commitment made.</p><p>I was looking for the checkout counter, a familiar face showed up.</p><p>T.</p><p>It feels weird to have dreamt a person that was not in my core social circle and even had not been mentioned for years.</p><p>There is connection beyond that, of course.</p><p>No conversation, no interaction. Some eye contact,perhaps.</p><p>Not emotional, no tear.</p><p>Then further toward south.</p><p>Ann Arbor and Leuven are both a perfectly-shaped university town. A quasi-circle, major road in straight north-south and east-west directions. Sometimes it was reassuring, but I guess it is not important.</p><p>I know, the dream seems like something looking back and overly nostalgic. However, I felt different, as generally it was a light and mysterious atmosphere rather than a stressful one.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Self-Mumbling</category>
      
      <category>Day Dream</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Next Stop Heavenly Kingdom</title>
    <link href="/2024/02/14/Next-Stop-Heavenly-Kingdom/"/>
    <url>/2024/02/14/Next-Stop-Heavenly-Kingdom/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The title is misleading I guess. It’s Valentine’s day, please wave your hands to prove that you are happy.</p><p>Similar sentence may express some completely different emotions. From naively glad “if you’re happy and you know it, clap you hands!” to that lyrics resonating in my head.</p><p>A time series data could be constructed to reflect the number of celebrating holidays related to romantic relationship on one’s social media network. I had the feeling that somehow it’s increasing as people grow mature, while the very maturity discourages some ones to be more expressive.</p><p>We talked about how younger generations are celebrating the day for their loving parents, when I realized how unstable the date of Valentine might be for certain groups, as the Spring Festival is always somewhere close, plans had to be made to adjust the schedule. Well, lucky to some, no family business attached, free to explore the precious opportunity.</p><p>I am glad to say that some good memories of the day are carefully stored, and they endowed more emotional palpitation to those songs planted in our brains.</p><p>Leaves may fall down carrying the message from our Moon,</p><p>The Sun will benevolently glides over my nightstand, as always.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Self-Mumbling</category>
      
      <category>Random Thoughts</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Spring Festival</title>
    <link href="/2024/02/13/Spring-Festival/"/>
    <url>/2024/02/13/Spring-Festival/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>People may say we do not celebrate Spring Festival that much any more. “We were kinds forced to do so,” I quoted from a friend.</p><p>I would blame it to my being less passionate on everything, but to be specific on the matter of New Year, it could be something else.</p><p>It has been a non-traditional holiday for us for a long time. There was no much mandatory visits to relatives and other social settings. It was us being away from work and study, spending some relaxing time. In the years abroad, students may care less on the matter, but to compensate some inner eagers, there was always some little gatherings, or at least something ‘ritual’, say, watching one minute of the gala, making some food nice than usual…</p><p>But overall there’s no special feeling.</p><p>Not even caring about the debate of CNY and LNY anymore. Interestingly, myself three years ago, probably lot pinker than now, once criticized in the comment box when the school posted on instagram celebrating CNY, saying that there were fellow community members from other countries treasure that day.</p><p>BTW, I guess I should update at least once a week. Another session is coming up so I hope it would clear up my thoughts a bit more.</p><p>Chilling in the study room, facing the window. It’s snowing. Same location yesterday, the song Qiuyuqiulai came into my earbuds, how emotionally nostalgic.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Self-Mumbling</category>
      
      <category>Random Thoughts</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Domino&#39;s</title>
    <link href="/2024/02/05/Domino-s/"/>
    <url>/2024/02/05/Domino-s/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Fun fact: <strong>Domino’s</strong> was founded in <strong>Ann Arbor</strong>. To be precise, the first Domino’s was opened in the satellite city of Ann Arbor, <strong>Ypsilanti</strong>, by two brothers who were attending the U of M. Now it is a multinational pizza franchise with tens of thousand stores around the world.</p><p>For all these years living so close to a Domino’s, I probably only went there for less than 5 times. Although, the only few times I had with Domino’s were quite memorable.</p><ul><li>A cold winter midnight in late 2021 <strong>Ann Arbor</strong>. At that time I was totally screwed up by the Munger room. I went to bed at noon, woke up when all the places were closed at night. I found out there is a Domino’s nearby which closes at 3am according to Google Map. I walked there, trembling with cold weather, hunger, and sadly was told the store closed at 1am that day.</li><li>Start of Covid, <strong>Paris</strong>, one night in Jan 2020. Our SWERC trio got back to the hotel by train. The two Italians reluctantly followed me into a Domino’s, as we had not eaten since noon. We joked about how Domino’s was “American’s evil imitation of pizza” and laughed on how people from Italy ended up actually enjoying those American “pizza” in France.</li><li><strong>Beijing</strong>, summer 2017. IIRC my class was arranging a little gathering during lunch break since we were saying goodbye to Senior 2 of high school, heading to different paths soon. That day I was picking up the pizza orders with F. I don’t remember who organized the event, maybe J, or perhaps the teacher. I probably felt a bit awkward at the time, but the walk to the store quite joyful. F and I walked the same routine several times for class events. The destination was either a pizza store or the Carrefour.</li></ul><p>OK, the 2017 one was NOT Domino’s, my memory got mixed up. It was probably a local brand, <strong>Zhandian</strong>.</p><p>Anyway…I wrote that far. Today I simply remembered that day and hoped it was Domino’s. Nonetheless, it’s worth mentioning the mood of those days remotely associated with pizza.</p><ul><li>What was I thinking on the way back without pizza in my hand? Was it different from the nights <strong>singing</strong> alone on Brusselsestraat, Leuven?</li><li>Have I <strong>regrets</strong> not preparing more thoroughly before the tournament? Did we have any idea on what the world was going to <strong>change</strong> in that month?</li><li>Pizza, and the people, which were more enjoyable? Didn’t we forget to virtual connect with the <strong>friend</strong> thousand miles away from home?</li></ul><p>Wrote all these after eating a piece of Domino’s, huh?</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Self-Mumbling</category>
      
      <category>Food</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Elena Ferrante (1)</title>
    <link href="/2024/01/30/Elena-Ferrante-1/"/>
    <url>/2024/01/30/Elena-Ferrante-1/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>To be honest I have never seriously read <strong>Ferrante</strong> until very recently, although I claim myself as a big fan since long ago.</p><p>It was back in the last year of high school, when I became relatively free post-application. I spent a huge portion of time in bookstores, mainly <strong>Renda Mingde</strong> next to RDFZ’s east gate, <strong>Douban</strong>, and <strong>Wansheng</strong>. At the same time the first book of Neapolitan series, <strong>L’amica geniale</strong>, was translated and published in China. The sorta-weird Chinese title and the well-designed book covers appeared in front of me nearly everyday. Concurrently I was exposed to countless articles, critics, praises, and interviews online. I was fancied by the topic and storyline yet somehow I never purchased the book.</p><p>Ferrante was so popular that their books became a part of socializing from time to time. With information I gathered from articles and TV series clips I appeared as a fan in many occasions. Looking back, it seemed a bit <em>hypocritic</em>.</p><p>Nonetheless, the mystery of Ferrante actually helped me <em>academically</em> multiple times. Once for a presentation in a law course at LUISS, I used Ferrante as an example to discuss how <strong>copyright laws</strong> in different regions handle works published in <strong>pseudonyms</strong>. How should you <em>register</em> copyright under pseudonym, what is the <em>life cycle</em> of copyright if the author remain anonymous, what if the identity is <em>revealed</em> voluntarily, or even forcedly, what should you be careful about <em>translation</em> and publishing in <em>another</em> country, is any country requiring a <em>real legal name</em> registered in a <em>public</em> database, how other relatively old pseudonyms, such as Ellery Queen, are right now? It was a fun little research at the time.</p><p>Another case is <strong>Authorship Attribution</strong>, a popular topic in Natural Language Processing. There are many efforts made to unveil Ferrante’s true identity, including papers analyzing a huge of amount of candidates’ novels to perform unsupervised learning. Mentioned methods include Latent Dirichlet Allocation, Correspondence Analysis, Principle Component Analysis, Labbe’s “intertextual distance”, etc… It almost became a project for a NLP course I took before, yet it was not feasible as many corpora were not accessible.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Books</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>KMT-TPP Coop polling</title>
    <link href="/2024/01/28/KMT-TPP-Coop-polling/"/>
    <url>/2024/01/28/KMT-TPP-Coop-polling/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I am taking a course in <strong>sampling</strong> theory and design this semester.</p><p>I believe data collection, annotation, and processing are crucial and their importance is sometimes <strong>underestimated</strong>.</p><p>I am still a beginner in learning sampling. One example is doing analysis for Bridge by generating random boards by <a href="https://github.com/anntzer/redeal">redeal</a>, which I am always confused about what specification would make my analysis more trustworthy or accurate in respect to the specific scenario I am considering, and I always wondered to what extend the sample size compared to the theoretical possible combinations matters.</p><p>The other topic that intrigues me is political polling. Take the example of the potential cooperation of KMT and TPP in the previous Taiwan Election, there was a huge <a href="https://www.cna.com.tw/news/aipl/202311185003.aspx">disagreement</a> on the polling statistics and errors. I am putting my code running the simulation here, and the more theoretical discussion might be posted later.</p><figure class="highlight python"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br><span class="line">2</span><br><span class="line">3</span><br><span class="line">4</span><br><span class="line">5</span><br><span class="line">6</span><br><span class="line">7</span><br><span class="line">8</span><br><span class="line">9</span><br><span class="line">10</span><br><span class="line">11</span><br><span class="line">12</span><br><span class="line">13</span><br><span class="line">14</span><br><span class="line">15</span><br><span class="line">16</span><br><span class="line">17</span><br><span class="line">18</span><br><span class="line">19</span><br><span class="line">20</span><br><span class="line">21</span><br><span class="line">22</span><br><span class="line">23</span><br><span class="line">24</span><br><span class="line">25</span><br><span class="line">26</span><br><span class="line">27</span><br><span class="line">28</span><br><span class="line">29</span><br><span class="line">30</span><br><span class="line">31</span><br><span class="line">32</span><br><span class="line">33</span><br><span class="line">34</span><br><span class="line">35</span><br><span class="line">36</span><br><span class="line">37</span><br><span class="line">38</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><code class="hljs python"><span class="hljs-keyword">import</span> numpy <span class="hljs-keyword">as</span> np<br><br>np.random.seed(<span class="hljs-number">111</span>)<br><br><span class="hljs-keyword">def</span> <span class="hljs-title function_">estimate_CI</span>(<span class="hljs-params">supportKeHou, supportLaiXiao1, supportHouKe, supportLaiXiao2, </span><br><span class="hljs-params">                simulation_count=<span class="hljs-number">10000</span>, sample_size=<span class="hljs-number">1000</span></span>):<br>    <span class="hljs-string">&#x27;&#x27;&#x27;</span><br><span class="hljs-string">    Simulation of LanBaiHe </span><br><span class="hljs-string">    supportKeHou: float in [0,1], support rate for KeHou against LaiXiao</span><br><span class="hljs-string">    supportHouKe: float in [0,1], support rate for HouKe against LaiXiao</span><br><span class="hljs-string">    supportLaiXiao1 &amp; supportLaiXiao2: float [0,1], support rate for LaiXiao against Kehou(1) or HouKe(2)</span><br><span class="hljs-string">    simulation_count: positive int, number of simulations to run</span><br><span class="hljs-string">    sample_size: number of votes casted in the poll</span><br><span class="hljs-string">    &#x27;&#x27;&#x27;</span><br>    <br>    <span class="hljs-comment"># Randomly choose #sample_size elements from [1, -1, 0] with respective support rates as prob</span><br>    <span class="hljs-comment"># where 1 denotes LanBaiHe, -1 denotes LaiXiao, 0 denotes voting for neither of them</span><br>    <span class="hljs-comment"># the sum of each choice result divided by sample_size is the sopport rate difference of LanBaihe over LaiXiao </span><br>    <span class="hljs-comment"># Run this random choice # simulation_count times</span><br>    result1 = np.array([<span class="hljs-built_in">sum</span>(np.random.choice([<span class="hljs-number">1</span>, -<span class="hljs-number">1</span>, <span class="hljs-number">0</span>], sample_size, <br>                                             p=[supportKeHou, supportLaiXiao1, <span class="hljs-number">1</span>- supportKeHou - supportLaiXiao1])) / sample_size <br>                        <span class="hljs-keyword">for</span> _ <span class="hljs-keyword">in</span> <span class="hljs-built_in">range</span>(simulation_count)])<br>    result2 = np.array([<span class="hljs-built_in">sum</span>(np.random.choice([<span class="hljs-number">1</span>, -<span class="hljs-number">1</span>, <span class="hljs-number">0</span>], sample_size, <br>                                             p=[supportHouKe, supportLaiXiao2, <span class="hljs-number">1</span>- supportHouKe - supportLaiXiao2])) / sample_size <br>                        <span class="hljs-keyword">for</span> _ <span class="hljs-keyword">in</span> <span class="hljs-built_in">range</span>(simulation_count)])<br>    <span class="hljs-comment"># Get the differnece of these two differences</span><br>    <span class="hljs-comment"># Calculate the mean and std</span><br>    dif_mean = np.mean(result1 - result2)<br>    dif_std = np.std(result1 - result2)<br>    <span class="hljs-built_in">print</span>(<span class="hljs-string">f&quot;柯胜赖-侯胜赖:<span class="hljs-subst">&#123;dif_mean&#125;</span>\n标准差:<span class="hljs-subst">&#123;dif_std&#125;</span>\n95%CI:[<span class="hljs-subst">&#123;dif_mean - <span class="hljs-number">1.96</span> * dif_std&#125;</span>,<span class="hljs-subst">&#123;dif_mean + <span class="hljs-number">1.96</span> * dif_std&#125;</span>]&quot;</span>)<br><br><span class="hljs-comment"># poll_1</span><br><span class="hljs-built_in">print</span>(<span class="hljs-string">&#x27;Poll #1&#x27;</span>)<br>estimate_CI(<span class="hljs-number">0.483</span>, <span class="hljs-number">0.392</span>, <span class="hljs-number">0.461</span>, <span class="hljs-number">0.416</span>, sample_size=<span class="hljs-number">2046</span>)<br><br><span class="hljs-comment"># poll_4</span><br><span class="hljs-built_in">print</span>(<span class="hljs-string">&#x27;Poll #4&#x27;</span>)<br>estimate_CI(<span class="hljs-number">0.4601</span>, <span class="hljs-number">0.3222</span>, <span class="hljs-number">0.4082</span>, <span class="hljs-number">0.3586</span>, sample_size=<span class="hljs-number">1112</span>)<br></code></pre></td></tr></table></figure>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Self-Mumbling</category>
      
      <category>Data Science and Life</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Kobe</title>
    <link href="/2024/01/27/Kobe/"/>
    <url>/2024/01/27/Kobe/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A few people are remembering Kobe.</p><p>I am never an enthusiastic basketball fan, only a period of supporting the Beijing Jinyu &#x2F; Shougang in their golden era. But Kobe seemed to represent something higher than the sport itself.</p><p>Four years ago, after an interesting run in SWERC, Michele, Francesco, and I were sightseeing Paris. Some most famous places were dropped by, phone calls and texts were made with friends in Roma, and then we were on late train back to the suburban hotel we stayed.</p><p>It was tiring. Of course, we just finished a day of coding and then lecture-attending. At that time covid was merely a quasi-joke to all of us, along with rumors of severe lockdown and laughs on bats. </p><p>It was on the train when Francesco and I both caught the breaking news of Kobe Bryant. The news seemed fake to us, so in the following 5 minutes, we were trying to figure out if there was a trustworthy news agency reporting it. We all know it was true.</p><p>Michele, probably with zero interest in sports, asked who Kobe was. </p><p>At that moment, we were too tired and busy to respond anything more than “a famous American basketball player.” Then I started thinking about the Leicester Chairman who died in the same way. Leicester was part of the spirit of my high school years. So, yeah, I can relate.</p><p>Then I started to remember the day of Kobe’s last game. We were at Mr. Yang’s Geology class. He is a super fan himself, so during the class, watching live stream was allowed, and stats were updated from time to time. For the ‘now’ version of myself, if I were to think about that day long enough, I’d definitely cry. </p><p>2020 seemed to start with some tragedies, and more severe ones followed. Now as we look back, it seemed that maybe all was written on the wall long ago. But, to be honest, it really depends on your point of view, as there were &#x2F; are so many events happened that you can choose as symbolic ones, which could eventually lead to completely different ways of interpretations. </p><p>Maybe what I am saying is that, the shock is long gone, and the time series is going to explore their randomness as planned.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Sports</category>
      
      <category>Basketball</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Si Jiahui</title>
    <link href="/2024/01/19/Si-Jiahui/"/>
    <url>/2024/01/19/Si-Jiahui/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Si_Jiahui"><strong><em>Si Jiahui’s</em></strong></a> magnificent performance at the <strong>2023 World Snooker Championship</strong> was a source of energy for me during those days. Even though he <em>suffered</em> from one of the <strong>greatest comeback</strong> in Snooker history against <strong><em>Luca Brecel</em></strong> in the semi-final, his <em>sniper-like potting style</em>, his <em>braveness</em>, and his <em>energetic youthness</em> made a huge impact on me. It was pure <em>happiness</em> and joy. To be honest, I am <strong>not</strong> a fan of great comebacks in sports, and I always believe there is a certain <strong>threshold</strong> to call a game settled. Such as <em>100 imps</em> behind in a <strong>bridge</strong> knockout game before the last session, or <strong>PSG’s four-goal lead</strong> in the CL against Barcelona. I feel that there should be a sense of <em>respect</em> or composure to not try turning the wave around after passing a certain point. But the <em>cruel</em> yet <em>fascinating</em> truth is that, sports, and life, is all about <strong><em>fantastic unbelievable comebacks</em></strong>. Players all know that they should treat it as an <em>even</em> game and give their <em>best</em> until the final score is ended for sure.</p><p>At that time I was eager to read more about him and to share the stories, so I <strong>translated</strong> an <a href="https://news.hangzhou.com.cn/zjnews/content/2021-04/01/content_7939366_0.html">old news from Hangzhou</a> and post it on <strong><em>reddit</em></strong>. Life is a long game with endless loses and comebacks. Or perhaps, it’s not judged in quantifiable results. Anyway, I wish Jiahui be in <strong>top 16</strong> soon.</p><p>Please enjoy his story.</p><h2 id="Si-Jiahui’s-childhood-story"><a href="#Si-Jiahui’s-childhood-story" class="headerlink" title="Si Jiahui’s childhood story"></a>Si Jiahui’s childhood story</h2><p>Originally posted <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/snooker/comments/130u0bz/si_jiahuis_childhood_how_he_became_professional/">here</a></p><p>Jiahui was born in 2002 at Dongbaihu county, Zhuji city, Zhejiang province. His family moved to Hangzhou (Zhejiang’s capital), where he grew up. He showed some sports talent in elementary school, “he won second-place in school’s Ping Pong tournament,” quote his father Si Peijun, “his coach said if he had started Ping Pong earlier, he would have achieved something huge.”</p><p>At Jiahui’s 4th grade, his father opened a small pool club where people play Chinese 8-ball. Jiahui became obsessed with the game. Si took bus everyday afterschool to the club to play pool.</p><p>Once his father set up a game between Jiahui and one of the club’s regular player, Jiahui beat him easily, and after 3 months practice, he was able to beat everyone in the club.</p><p>Later that summer, Jiahui’s father took him to a training camp to start learning snooker systematically. After half a month, Jiahui finished runner-up in a east China regional elementary school 9-ball tournament.</p><p>During that tournament, the Jiahui and Peijun encountered father from Ningbo (Zhejiang), who claimed that his son already quitted school and started practicing snooker in Guangdong province. Later back home, Jiahui told his father that he wanted to quit school and become professional snooker player.</p><p>His parents were shocked. They believed in Jiahui’s talent, but they never thought he should quit school. “I turned him down at least 3 times,” says Peijun, “but he was really persistent and self-determined.”</p><p>After consulting with professional snooker coaches, they family finally decided to accompany Jiahui to Guangdong to learn snooker in September, 2013.</p><p>Being asked why he chose snooker instead of other pool varieties, Jiahui said:” it’s because of Ronnie O’Sullivan, his game is so smooth and beautiful, and I dream to play at that stage one day.”</p><p>In Guangdong, Jiahui practiced snooker 8-10 hours per day. He only rested half a day every week, and went to movies with his father to relax.</p><p>He trained very hard, having sore arms all the time. His father would help him as much as he could. Sometimes Jiahui could not fall asleep at night, so he just got up and kept potting balls.</p><p>The reporter asked if he had ever considered giving up, Jiahui answered:” there was a time when I had a run of bad form and kept losing, I did consider giving up.” Eventually his parents’ encouragement helped him get through the difficult time.</p><p>In June, 2019, Jiahui flew to UK for Q-school. Beyond their expectation, Jiahui won a two-year tour card. He became the first professional snooker player from Zhejiang and started to practice in UK.</p><p>Living abroad alone was not easy for Jiahui. His left eye had an allergy and had to had a small surgery. The food was another issue, he usually took takeouts and he lost a lot of weights. Being 1.86m (6’1’’), his weight dropped from 81kg (178lb) to 63kg (139lb) at that time.</p><p>However, Jiahui embraced the challenge. He told reporter: “Eye problem is no big deal. As for food, takeouts are not tasty, but his roommate cooks nice food.”</p><p>According to Jiahui’s father, China’s snooker population is growing rapidly, and many families are considering letting their kids play professionally. He admits that it was a extremely tough road to come through, Jiahui’s talent and determination were essential to his success, and he advices other family to think twice before making the decision.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Sports</category>
      
      <category>Snooker</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>cold</title>
    <link href="/2024/01/18/cold/"/>
    <url>/2024/01/18/cold/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It’s cold. Now I seriously feel it. Not like before, when I spent most of time indoors. You are greeted by merciless freezing breezes on the way.</p><p>I do love snow. It is enjoyable simply watching the snow. It could be hypocritical, though, as I never encountered heavier snow in much more northern part of the world.</p><p>One thing I read somewhere is that people here seem to care little about the weather. No matter it is rainy or snowy, residents keep their life busy as usual, walking on the pavements with no difference from any other day.</p><p>I kept staring at the footprints on the snow today while walking towards classroom building. I wondered, how many people had stepped on this part of the road since dawn, could I make an estimation of the number by observing the patterns of the footprints, how accurate would my estimation be?</p><p>Including the ones that were already semi-covered by the newly fallen snows, the numbers seemed to be around 20. “That was quite a small number,” I thought. Well, I did not know when the snow started, so I had little idea on the timeframe for this estimation.</p><p>If you engage with the snow, the coldness, fun will come. A snowman seems like something stable, concrete, something reliable. A sense of upward joyful feeling is erupting from their bodies. Football on the snow, guys could feel the mixture of solidness and crunchiness under their feet. Even on some desperate days, snow on the roof track is served as something comforting.</p><p>Loneliness is always there, too. It could be the time no one cares to join the snowman building, or the time everyone is happily fighting while one is left aside. It’s not about snow, or cold, anymore.</p><p>But, when staring at the footprints, heads down, wondering where have all the young men gone, you saw smiles, friendly nods, casual chats…</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Self-Mumbling</category>
      
      <category>Random Thoughts</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Past Lives (film 2023)</title>
    <link href="/2024/01/13/Past-Lives-film-2023/"/>
    <url>/2024/01/13/Past-Lives-film-2023/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have imagined and dreamt about <strong>reunion</strong> with an <em>old friend</em> many times. Different reunions, with different friends. It could be a <em>planned</em> get-together, or a <em>surprise</em> encounter. I wonder how we would <em>behave</em>, what <em>facial expressions</em> we would have, and what would be <em>said</em>, what would happen <em>later…</em></p><p>First time we re-united at the baggage claim of Fiumicino terminal, I thought <em>a hundred</em> ways of how we would react seeing each other, but it turned out to be an <em>awkward</em> one, simply holding each one’s own luggage and some <em>eye contact</em>. “We should have <strong>kissed and hugged</strong>,” we agreed later. There was a <em>learning curve</em>, later reunion moments, like after lockdown and after Leuven, turned out to be more <em>natural</em>. </p><p>There’s also that day K and I finally going to meet after more than two years. I arrived first at the square in front of Buffalo city hall, wondering if there was going to be a <em>hug</em>, or a <em>handshake</em>, or whatever seems dramatic or passionate. </p><p>And <strong>dreams</strong>, all dreams about happy, surprised faces of two old friends meeting on the street, long tight embracement, exclamation, and other stereotypical movie stuff. </p><p>Also, <strong>long goodbyes</strong>. <em>Wave</em> hands? <em>Shake</em> hands? <em>Hug</em>? <em>Kiss</em>? <strong>What kind of kiss?</strong> <strong>What kind of hug?</strong> Just <em>smile</em>? What <em>words</em>? In what <strong>tone</strong>? Would someone <em>turn and look back</em> while leaving? Perhaps one would return because some belongings were <em>accidently left behind</em>? </p><p>However, no matter what imaginations are, in reality, in most of the times, they almost <strong>never occur</strong>. Many times people like us are just <em>afraid to express</em>, but the happiness is <em>genuine</em>. </p><p>Surprising or planned, there are going to be <em>endless</em> reunions and goodbyes ahead of you. You gonna change, others gonna change, and probably there’s only a <em>handful</em> of people that you would have that strong stream of emotions prepared to be released. My point is that, the movie catches this quite <em>“east Asian”</em> type of feelings quite well, and it happens often, not just on friends with some intimate history, simply on good <strong>friends</strong>. And gender does <strong>not</strong> matter, there are ones who are <em>pursuing dreams</em> in a cool or painful way, and ones who are <em>stuck</em> in <strong>traditional</strong> ways of living and trapped by traditional values. </p><p>Anyway, the auditorium was quite <em>full</em> today. I felt <em>related</em>, but I did not <em>cry</em>. </p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Movies and TV</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Corso d&#39;italiano</title>
    <link href="/2024/01/12/Corso-d-italiano/"/>
    <url>/2024/01/12/Corso-d-italiano/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Oggi ho frequentato il mio primo <strong>corso di italiano</strong> dopo <em>quattro</em> anni. È un corso dedicato agli studenti che hanno studiato italiano per almeno <em>due</em> anni. In generale, il professore, <strong>Leonardo</strong>, vuole che pratichiamo l’ascolto e la conversazione in italiano attraverso lo studio del <strong><em>teatro</em></strong>. Mi interessa molto, ma è un po’ difficile per me capire al cento per cento. Comunque, nella prima lezione, ci sono stati presentati i tipi di lettura (<strong>lettura tipo</strong>) e abbiamo dovuto presentare il teso con emozioni diverse. Ho provato il tipo <em>arrabbiato</em>. Ero un po’ nervoso, e la mia presentazione non è andata bene. </p><p>La classe è piacevole, ci sono studenti <strong>internazionali</strong> e un <strong>professore anziano</strong> che insegna medicina. C’è anche qualcuno che utilizza un <strong>pronome non binario</strong>. Dopo la lezione, ho parlato di <strong>Pirandello</strong>, <strong>Calvino</strong> e di <strong><em>Morte Accidentale di un Anarchico</em></strong>. La conversazione è in inglese, sfortunatamente, perché non sono sicuro di parlare bene Italiano.</p><p>Anyway, I chose an Italiano course, <em>just for fun not for credit</em>. Hopefully I can meet new people, make friends, and ensure that I can speak a fair amount of Italian in the future opportunities. </p><p>The element of theatre is a plus. There were certainly <em>flashbacks</em> of us playing the <strong>Tea House</strong>. If I’m truly prone to hide my emotions, perhaps playing a role is a perfect way to both <em>express</em> and provide a <em>façade</em>. </p><p>Surprisingly there was a debate on my choice. It’s already a stage that I developed a quite unique view on my major, my future plans, and things I like. Yet those can not be fully expressed and put into serious actions, as I am not independent.  </p><p>This brings to the fact that I went to my <em>first</em> counseling session since everything suddenly ended last year. Wow I guess I spoke my most fluent English when I was talking about myself with the assurance of <em>confidentiality</em> and no burden. Hopefully two aims would be achieved: say things I want to say, things that I may even not want to write down; and get help to go through this restarted journey. </p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Self-Mumbling</category>
      
      <category>Random Thoughts</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>I walk fast</title>
    <link href="/2024/01/08/I-walk-fast/"/>
    <url>/2024/01/08/I-walk-fast/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I walk <strong>fast</strong>, especially when I am walking <strong>alone</strong>.</p><p>In my memory, there are only <em>two</em> friends that I feel who walk <em>significantly faster</em> than me.</p><p>While walking alone, no matter what situation it is, where I am, whether I am familiar with the surroundings, I do not feel obliged to be afraid. There is reasonable amount of <em>caution</em>, if course.</p><p>Things are quite different when I have <em>company</em>. </p><p>Walking in a large group on the road is worth researching. Firstly, I hate when we or some others are <strong>blocking</strong> the whole width of the road, so I tend not to walk side by side if there are already some doing so. As a result, in these years I am the one who walk <strong>behind</strong> the major crowd, sometimes ahead, if there is need to <strong>overtake</strong> them. It may feel a bit <em>inferior</em> from time to time, and I might be <em>discouraged</em> to talk more due to that kind of feeling. I remember that, four years ago, I was the person in <em>“excited Saturday”</em> mood, walking side by side with close friends, <em>both</em> arms on their shoulders. </p><p>Another interesting point is that if I walk ahead, I cannot help but frequently <strong><em>look back</em></strong>. This happens in many occasions, since if I was not walking with an intimate friend or engaged in continuous conversation, I may be walking ahead a few meters due to my usual walking speed. </p><p>But why looking back? Originally it could be a sense of <strong>responsibility</strong>. Back in years when I was leading a group of classmates or teammates on the road, it was my <em>duty</em> to ensure that no one was left behind. This also applies when I was walking with close friends. A later theory was that there might a sense of <strong>insecure</strong>. It means that I might not want to be alone. Even if I am in advantage position, I do not want my companions behind me, which worries me. However, weirdly, I do not have that bad type of loneliness while <em>actually</em> walking alone. It only happens when I do have someone walking with me. </p><p>Confidently walking alone is a <em>happiness</em>, so is having someone walking side-by-side. In former I feel <em>adventurous</em> and curious to unfold future; in latter it is my honor and privilege to treasure our <em>comradeship</em>.  </p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Self-Mumbling</category>
      
      <category>Who Am I</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Sense or Sensibility</title>
    <link href="/2024/01/04/0104/"/>
    <url>/2024/01/04/0104/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>Lilic</em> said on graduation day that <strong><em>“be grateful that we are living in a society that respects science.”</em></strong></p><p>At that time there was a bit heated quarrel on the topic of visiting a <em>daoist</em> mountain on a foggy day. I guess that was a taste on the adult real world.</p><p>Growing up we value logic, reason, and science. Yet these years I witnessed many methodologies that were quite different. They are not the complete opposite, such as feverous superstition or zealous religion. Usually, elements of <em>myth, sentiment, emotion, perception, conscience</em>, and something close to superstition (believing in something not by some logical reasons) consist most of them.</p><p>And I do that too from time to time.</p><p>And it’s hard to draw the line between something awfully wrong and those sound humane.</p><p>Sometimes it’s a runaway from the correct and difficult road and way of thinking, sometimes you may feel that’s actually a valid path that just you were told to despise before.</p><p>A balance is probably the better option, and lots of suppression and confusion are required.</p><p>Ok just some inspiration. There’s lot’s of terms I don’t know how to express in English, so let’s finish it <em>later</em>.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Self-Mumbling</category>
      
      <category>Early Days</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>New Year&#39;s Eve 1231 2023</title>
    <link href="/2024/01/01/New-Year-s-Eve-1231-2023/"/>
    <url>/2024/01/01/New-Year-s-Eve-1231-2023/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Passing-the-New-Year’s-Eve"><a href="#Passing-the-New-Year’s-Eve" class="headerlink" title="Passing the New Year’s Eve."></a>Passing the New Year’s Eve.</h2><p>I have not had a so-called proper New Year’s Eve celebration for years. </p><ul><li><p>End of 2022, bunch of <strong><em>Bridge</em></strong> enthusiasts who just lost the game were in a hotel room watching football game and eating Chinese takeout.</p></li><li><p>End of 2021, I barely remember. About that time, I was trying to make things better, writing reflections, and telling Khaled that I found <strong><em>Daredevil</em></strong> super cool.</p></li><li><p>End of 2020, in the heist of <strong><em>quarantine and 12 am curfew</em></strong>, I walked to Leuven downtown, singing Beyond’s Amani, shouting “happy new year” to the young biker guys and old woman who were passing by on <em>Brusselsestraat</em>. </p></li><li><p>End of 2019, regretedly E and me <em>never</em> spent New Year’s Eve together. I was in Beijing, chilling in my room while my parents watching <strong>Alan Tam</strong> and the <strong>Five Tigers of the Wynners</strong>. </p></li><li><p>End of 2018, just got back to Roma from my first solo trip, eating poorly cooked <em>Barilla</em>.</p></li><li><p>End of 2017, freezing in bedroom, trying to catch up with application <em>deadline</em>.</p></li><li><p>2016, no memory, probably staying up late at school after <em>New Year Gala</em>.</p></li><li><p>2015 was by far my favorite. Bunch of old friends, still had not figured out what high school was, yelling, singing, taking pictures on the school field. <em>如果有来生以及更多</em></p></li></ul><p>Not a good pattern. Let’s make sure 2023 is the worst.</p><p>I do wish it could be like what’s in the TV for once. Snowy, crowds gathering on the street or friends squeezing on a sofa, warm atmosphere, crying out loud, and hugging and kissing…</p><p>Anyway, time to chant “Always look at the <em>b<strong>r</strong>ight</em> side of life” with a <em>retroflex</em> <strong><em>R</em></strong>. Happy new year.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Self-Mumbling</category>
      
      <category>Random Thoughts</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>2023 Books</title>
    <link href="/2023/12/31/2023-Books/"/>
    <url>/2023/12/31/2023-Books/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="Books-I-read-in-2023"><a href="#Books-I-read-in-2023" class="headerlink" title="Books I read in 2023"></a>Books I read in 2023</h1><p>Luckily I had time to read some this year. There are about 3 categories: Detective Novels that I read for fun and leisure; books about Revolution; and other literatures.</p><h2 id="Mysteries-and-Detective-Novels"><a href="#Mysteries-and-Detective-Novels" class="headerlink" title="Mysteries and Detective Novels:"></a>Mysteries and Detective Novels:</h2><p>I wish that I will always have an unread <strong>Agatha Christie</strong> book on the shelf, because it would be the best way to pass a sunny afternoon. One may just enjoy reading on the sofa with sunshine pouring on the papers, and one never has to bother remembering any details afterwards.</p><p>This year, three of her masterpieces were appreciated.</p><ul><li><p>   <strong><em>The Mysterious Affair at Styles</em></strong>. The very first story of <strong>Poirot</strong>. Never a fan of <em>poisons</em>, I have to admit.</p></li><li><p>   <strong><em>A Murder is Announced</em></strong>. The first <strong>Miss Marple</strong> book I read. Not quite impressive. Only things I recall are the nicknames of the sisters and a cat named <em>Tiglath-Pileser</em>, which was the Assyrian King whose name my high school history teacher claimed to be the most difficult to memorize. </p></li><li><p>   <strong><em>Evil Under the Sun</em></strong>. A signature demonstration of Agatha’s <em>feminism</em>. A woman romantically involved with more than one man is often judged harshly and receives unjust speculation, yet for most of the times she herself would be the vulnerable victim in the end.</p></li></ul><p>There is also <strong><em>The Day of the Jackal</em></strong>. I bought the book in 2019 simply because it is on a top list of detective novels of all time. Having observed how people reacted to <strong>Shinzo Abe</strong>’s death and reading <strong>Boris Savinkov</strong>’s biography, I developed an interest into assassination stories. Is <em>political assassination</em> against single target without casualty on civilians in a non-democratic country justifiable? I wonder how similar C is to the countries like R and F 50-100 years ago, and if similar incident may happen. </p><h2 id="Revolution"><a href="#Revolution" class="headerlink" title="Revolution:"></a>Revolution:</h2><p>I somehow believe that it is imminent and I should at least theoretically and emotionally be prepared. I fancy stories from late 19th century to early 20th century, when a whole spectrum of revolutionary ideologies was being put into experiment and actions repeatedly.</p><ul><li><p>   <strong><em>Every Man a King</em></strong>. The autobiography of <strong>Huey Long</strong>. I wrote about him <a href="%5Blink%5D(https://fredfreddo.github.io/2023/12/26/1227/)">here</a>. Imagine if he had lived on and run against <strong>FDR</strong>, what would have happened?</p></li><li><p>   <strong><em>Rebel Girl</em></strong>. An Autobiography of <strong>Elizabeth Gurley Flynn</strong>, an Irish American social activist. The book focused on her early career and how she worked with <em>International Workers of the World</em> (IWW), delivered speech to crowds since middle school, and organized countless strikes that profoundly promoted workers rights in the U.S. There was one paragraph of her seeing people in Chinese restaurant celebrating in <em>1912</em>. I have imagined that kind of scene happening to me many times before. Myself in 2020 was expecting to celebrate <em>Unification</em> before my Leuven exchange ended, but now I am convinced that there is something more important. </p></li><li><p>   <strong><em>Rosa Luxemburg</em></strong>. A biography written by <strong>Paul Frolich</strong>, a left-wing journalist who survived till 1953. <em>Haymarket Books</em> republished the book in 2010 and I got that from a bookstore in <em>Buffalo</em> in 2022.</p></li><li><p>   Two books by <strong>John Reed</strong>: <strong><em>The War in Eastern Europe</em></strong>, <strong><em>Insurgent Mexico</em></strong>. I have said many times that Reed had one of the most romantic and adventurous lives I could hope for. After graduation, he lived with <strong>Pancho Villa</strong>’s men in the early years of the long <em>Mexican Revolution</em>. I am pleased every time to see the optimism and friendliness of these revolutionists, as it is like a reinforcement of stating that a bright future is ahead. The Eastern Europe book accounts his adventures on the front in <em>Serbia, Ottoman Empire, Romania, and Russia</em> during the WWI earlier years before Bulgaria joined the war. <strong>Boardman Robinson</strong>’s sketches helped delivered the tragic of a poor yet belligerent region. Interestingly they played <em>Bridge</em> for a week when detained in a hotel by Russian military officials. Reed was a <em>Harvard</em> alumnus. (Two main way to promote <em>Bridge</em>: by <em>blood</em>, or by a <em>prestigious school</em>.)</p></li><li><p>   <strong><em>Animal Farm</em></strong>. I guess it is never too late to read it.</p></li><li><p>   <strong><em>二手时间</em></strong>, by <strong>Svetlana Alexievich</strong>. It is surprising to see so many real and fictious stories that look exactly the same to our people’s history and present. Sometimes it is a torment to read, as we cannot see the way out. Like those lyrics said, “want to <em>break free</em>, yet not able to face it.”</p></li><li><p>   <strong><em>无路可逃</em></strong> &amp; <strong><em>一百个人的十年</em></strong> by <strong>冯骥才</strong>. <em>Cultural Revolution</em> is revolution, is it? L once said that during the covid years of 2020 to 2023 people were exactly <em>“no place to escape.”</em> People nowadays are warning for a second CR, yet interestingly, the last one is <em>left-wing</em>, and the coming one is <em>far-right</em>. </p></li><li><p>   <strong><em>天国之秋</em></strong> by <strong>Stephen Platt</strong>. I recognized the author since reading <strong><em>湖南人与现代中国</em></strong>, one of the most inspiring reading experiences I got that helped shape my <em>self-identity</em>. Platt’s book focused on the importance of foreign intervention and the charisma of <strong>Hong Ren-Gan</strong>. </p></li><li><p>   <strong><em>Morte Accidentale di un Anarchico</em></strong>. <em>Piazza Fontana, la luna rossa e rossa di violenza</em>. I guess I should be ready for next semester’s Italian course.</p></li><li><p>   <strong><em>五四运动史</em></strong>, by <strong>Chow Tse-Tsung</strong>. A best place to look for analogies for all the unspeakable <em>student movements</em> of this country, as May the Fourth is luckily the source of <em>legitimacy</em> of almost all parties. </p></li><li><p>   About 1848: <strong><em>1848, Year of Revolution</em></strong>, by <strong>Mike Rapport</strong>, a nice introduction to the revolutions in Europe from 1848-1851. I got to know <em>Repubblica Romana</em> of 1849 for the first time, and hoped to read more romance on <strong>Mazzini</strong> and <strong>Garibaldi</strong>. Therefore, I tried <strong><em>Gadfly</em></strong>, and was disappointed. What a shame to tell this kind of story with the background of revolution. I read <strong><em>18th Brumaire of Louis Bonaparte</em></strong> and <strong><em>The Civil War in France</em></strong> written by <strong>Marx</strong>. To be honest, I was not able to comprehend anything.</p></li><li><p>   <strong><em>北京法源寺</em></strong> by <strong>李敖</strong>. Those Hunanese reformer and revolutionist are always inspiring to me. My family visited the temple later in a cold winter Saturday. Unfortunately, I could not get access to the relics the book mentioned. There was a lovely <em>black cat</em>, and a group of people attending the ritual of embracing <em>Buddhism</em>.</p></li></ul><h2 id="Literature-in-general"><a href="#Literature-in-general" class="headerlink" title="Literature in general:"></a>Literature in general:</h2><ul><li><p>   <strong><em>酒吧长谈</em></strong> by <strong>Mario Llosa</strong>. A mind-blowing reading adventure. A perfectly-comprehensible <em>multi-thread</em> storytelling. I guess it could be put under Revolution category too, but it’s more about a young enthusiastic drifting away from ideals. I got the book in 2018 when I was still taking that Spanish elementary course in RDFZ, and I would practice pronouncing <em>“Conversación en La catedral”</em> every night going to bed.</p></li><li><p>   <strong><em>The Master and Margarita</em></strong>. <strong>Mikhail Bulgakov</strong>. I got the book from a blind book-exchange game organized by <em>ESN</em> at <em>Language Café</em> of LUISS in April 2019. I swapped out my <strong><em>Panama Papers</em></strong> as I guessed that I may not pass our custom. I suppose not all craziness is attractive to me and I seriously know little about religion.</p></li><li><p>   <strong><em>纽约客</em></strong>(白先勇). If I had read it in 2018, I promise I would have got <em>sentimental</em>. </p></li><li><p>   <strong><em>海都物语</em></strong>, by <strong>塩野七生</strong>. Simply wanted to read of the history of <em>Venice Republic</em>. What a heroic history of Republican ideas in actions of <em>pragmatists</em>.</p></li><li><p>   Two books about Prussia and German Empire as a by-product of addiction to <em>Paradox Interactives</em> games. <strong><em>不含传说的普鲁士</em></strong> by <strong>Sebastian Haffner</strong>, and <strong><em>脆弱的崛起</em></strong> by <strong>徐弃郁</strong>. There’s already serious comparisons of our situation to Germany’s in pre-WWI era. Beware: please make more <em>friends</em>.</p></li><li><p>   <strong><em>蛙</em></strong> by <strong>莫言</strong>. First time reading his book. How about a <em>sequel</em> of new generations?</p></li><li><p>   <strong><em>Steppenwolf</em></strong> by <strong>Hermann Hesse</strong>. All I was thinking: wow the protagonist in already <em>50</em>?</p></li><li><p>   <strong><em>野草 故事新篇</em></strong>. Please forgive me for not completing my high school reading requirement. I felt T made Lu-Xun an <em>icon close to God</em> in my class at that time, and I remember the serious-looking face of my jocular desk-mate when he was reading <strong><em>坟</em></strong>.</p></li><li><p>   <strong><em>与时俱进的启蒙</em></strong> by <strong>徐贲</strong>. Thankfully he is still publishing books. The materials matter less than the <em>reassurance</em> that there is still <em>light shining into my room</em>.</p></li></ul>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Books</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>Mystery</tag>
      
      <tag>Detective novels</tag>
      
      <tag>Revolution</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>test_post</title>
    <link href="/2023/12/30/test-post/"/>
    <url>/2023/12/30/test-post/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is a test blog by yfq32<br>copyright：<a href="https://markdown-it.github.io/">https://markdown-it.github.io/</a></p><h1 id="h1-Heading-8"><a href="#h1-Heading-8" class="headerlink" title="h1 Heading 8-)"></a>h1 Heading 8-)</h1><h2 id="h2-Heading"><a href="#h2-Heading" class="headerlink" title="h2 Heading"></a>h2 Heading</h2><h3 id="h3-Heading"><a href="#h3-Heading" class="headerlink" title="h3 Heading"></a>h3 Heading</h3><h4 id="h4-Heading"><a href="#h4-Heading" class="headerlink" title="h4 Heading"></a>h4 Heading</h4><h5 id="h5-Heading"><a href="#h5-Heading" class="headerlink" title="h5 Heading"></a>h5 Heading</h5><h6 id="h6-Heading"><a href="#h6-Heading" class="headerlink" title="h6 Heading"></a>h6 Heading</h6><h2 id="Horizontal-Rules"><a href="#Horizontal-Rules" class="headerlink" title="Horizontal Rules"></a>Horizontal Rules</h2><hr><hr><hr><h2 id="Typographic-replacements"><a href="#Typographic-replacements" class="headerlink" title="Typographic replacements"></a>Typographic replacements</h2><p>Enable typographer option to see result.</p><p>(c) (C) (r) (R) (tm) (TM) (p) (P) +-</p><p>test.. test… test….. test?….. test!….</p><p>!!!!!! ???? ,,  – —</p><p>“Smartypants, double quotes” and ‘single quotes’</p><h2 id="Emphasis"><a href="#Emphasis" class="headerlink" title="Emphasis"></a>Emphasis</h2><p><strong>This is bold text</strong></p><p><strong>This is bold text</strong></p><p><em>This is italic text</em></p><p><em>This is italic text</em></p><p><del>Strikethrough</del></p><h2 id="Blockquotes"><a href="#Blockquotes" class="headerlink" title="Blockquotes"></a>Blockquotes</h2><blockquote><p>Blockquotes can also be nested…</p><blockquote><p>…by using additional greater-than signs right next to each other…</p><blockquote><p>…or with spaces between arrows.</p></blockquote></blockquote></blockquote><h2 id="Lists"><a href="#Lists" class="headerlink" title="Lists"></a>Lists</h2><p>Unordered</p><ul><li>Create a list by starting a line with <code>+</code>, <code>-</code>, or <code>*</code></li><li>Sub-lists are made by indenting 2 spaces:<ul><li>Marker character change forces new list start:<ul><li>Ac tristique libero volutpat at</li></ul><ul><li>Facilisis in pretium nisl aliquet</li></ul><ul><li>Nulla volutpat aliquam velit</li></ul></li></ul></li><li>Very easy!</li></ul><p>Ordered</p><ol><li><p>Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet</p></li><li><p>Consectetur adipiscing elit</p></li><li><p>Integer molestie lorem at massa</p></li><li><p>You can use sequential numbers…</p></li><li><p>…or keep all the numbers as <code>1.</code></p></li></ol><p>Start numbering with offset:</p><ol start="57"><li>foo</li><li>bar</li></ol><h2 id="Code"><a href="#Code" class="headerlink" title="Code"></a>Code</h2><p>Inline <code>code</code></p><p>Indented code</p><pre><code class="hljs">// Some commentsline 1 of codeline 2 of codeline 3 of code</code></pre><p>Block code “fences”</p><figure class="highlight gams"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><code class="hljs gams"><span class="hljs-function"><span class="hljs-title">Sample</span></span> text here...<br></code></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>Syntax highlighting</p><figure class="highlight js"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br><span class="line">2</span><br><span class="line">3</span><br><span class="line">4</span><br><span class="line">5</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><code class="hljs js"><span class="hljs-keyword">var</span> foo = <span class="hljs-keyword">function</span> (<span class="hljs-params">bar</span>) &#123;<br>  <span class="hljs-keyword">return</span> bar++;<br>&#125;;<br><br><span class="hljs-variable language_">console</span>.<span class="hljs-title function_">log</span>(<span class="hljs-title function_">foo</span>(<span class="hljs-number">5</span>));<br></code></pre></td></tr></table></figure><h2 id="Tables"><a href="#Tables" class="headerlink" title="Tables"></a>Tables</h2><table><thead><tr><th>Option</th><th>Description</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td>data</td><td>path to data files to supply the data that will be passed into templates.</td></tr><tr><td>engine</td><td>engine to be used for processing templates. Handlebars is the default.</td></tr><tr><td>ext</td><td>extension to be used for dest files.</td></tr></tbody></table><p>Right aligned columns</p><table><thead><tr><th align="right">Option</th><th align="right">Description</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="right">data</td><td align="right">path to data files to supply the data that will be passed into templates.</td></tr><tr><td align="right">engine</td><td align="right">engine to be used for processing templates. Handlebars is the default.</td></tr><tr><td align="right">ext</td><td align="right">extension to be used for dest files.</td></tr></tbody></table><h2 id="Links"><a href="#Links" class="headerlink" title="Links"></a>Links</h2><p><a href="http://dev.nodeca.com/">link text</a></p><p><a href="http://nodeca.github.io/pica/demo/" title="title text!">link with title</a></p><p>Autoconverted link <a href="https://github.com/nodeca/pica">https://github.com/nodeca/pica</a> (enable linkify to see)</p><h2 id="Images"><a href="#Images" class="headerlink" title="Images"></a>Images</h2><p><img src="https://octodex.github.com/images/minion.png" alt="Minion"><br><img src="https://octodex.github.com/images/stormtroopocat.jpg" alt="Stormtroopocat" title="The Stormtroopocat"></p><p>Like links, Images also have a footnote style syntax</p><p><img src="https://octodex.github.com/images/dojocat.jpg" alt="Alt text" title="The Dojocat"></p><p>With a reference later in the document defining the URL location:</p><h2 id="Plugins"><a href="#Plugins" class="headerlink" title="Plugins"></a>Plugins</h2><p>The killer feature of <code>markdown-it</code> is very effective support of<br><a href="https://www.npmjs.org/browse/keyword/markdown-it-plugin">syntax plugins</a>.</p><h3 id="Emojies"><a href="#Emojies" class="headerlink" title="Emojies"></a><a href="https://github.com/markdown-it/markdown-it-emoji">Emojies</a></h3><blockquote><p>Classic markup: :wink: :cry: :laughing: :yum:</p><p>Shortcuts (emoticons): :-) :-( 8-) ;)</p></blockquote><p>see <a href="https://github.com/markdown-it/markdown-it-emoji#change-output">how to change output</a> with twemoji.</p><h3 id="Subscript-Superscript"><a href="#Subscript-Superscript" class="headerlink" title="Subscript &#x2F; Superscript"></a><a href="https://github.com/markdown-it/markdown-it-sub">Subscript</a> &#x2F; <a href="https://github.com/markdown-it/markdown-it-sup">Superscript</a></h3><ul><li>19^th^</li><li>H<del>2</del>O</li></ul><h3 id=""><a href="#" class="headerlink" title="&lt;ins&gt;"></a><a href="https://github.com/markdown-it/markdown-it-ins">&lt;ins&gt;</a></h3><p>++Inserted text++</p><h3 id="-1"><a href="#-1" class="headerlink" title="&lt;mark&gt;"></a><a href="https://github.com/markdown-it/markdown-it-mark">&lt;mark&gt;</a></h3><p>&#x3D;&#x3D;Marked text&#x3D;&#x3D;</p><h3 id="Footnotes"><a href="#Footnotes" class="headerlink" title="Footnotes"></a><a href="https://github.com/markdown-it/markdown-it-footnote">Footnotes</a></h3><p>Footnote 1 link[^first].</p><p>Footnote 2 link[^second].</p><p>Inline footnote^[Text of inline footnote] definition.</p><p>Duplicated footnote reference[^second].</p><p>[^first]: Footnote <strong>can have markup</strong></p><pre><code class="hljs">and multiple paragraphs.</code></pre><p>[^second]: Footnote text.</p><h3 id="Definition-lists"><a href="#Definition-lists" class="headerlink" title="Definition lists"></a><a href="https://github.com/markdown-it/markdown-it-deflist">Definition lists</a></h3><p>Term 1</p><p>:   Definition 1<br>with lazy continuation.</p><p>Term 2 with <em>inline markup</em></p><p>:   Definition 2</p><pre><code class="hljs">    &#123; some code, part of Definition 2 &#125;Third paragraph of definition 2.</code></pre><p><em>Compact style:</em></p><p>Term 1<br>  ~ Definition 1</p><p>Term 2<br>  ~ Definition 2a<br>  ~ Definition 2b</p><h3 id="Abbreviations"><a href="#Abbreviations" class="headerlink" title="Abbreviations"></a><a href="https://github.com/markdown-it/markdown-it-abbr">Abbreviations</a></h3><p>This is HTML abbreviation example.</p><p>It converts “HTML”, but keep intact partial entries like “xxxHTMLyyy” and so on.</p><p>*[HTML]: Hyper Text Markup Language</p><h3 id="Custom-containers"><a href="#Custom-containers" class="headerlink" title="Custom containers"></a><a href="https://github.com/markdown-it/markdown-it-container">Custom containers</a></h3><p>::: warning<br><em>here be dragons</em><br>:::</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>test_blog</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>test</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>2023 Movies and TV</title>
    <link href="/2023/12/30/1229/"/>
    <url>/2023/12/30/1229/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="SPOILER-ALERT"><a href="#SPOILER-ALERT" class="headerlink" title="SPOILER ALERT"></a>SPOILER ALERT</h2><p>I watched <strong><em>Where the Crawdads Sing</em></strong> (movie) this afternoon.</p><p>A film like that is a perfect closure for all the miseries this year started in January. At the beginning of 2023 I was blocking myself out in that dark room, watching the whole 7 seasons of <strong><em>Elementary</em></strong>. Crawdads came into my attention as I was looking for <strong>Daisy Edgar-Jones</strong>’ works. Her portrait of Marianne in <strong><em>Normal People</em></strong> was quite intriguing.</p><p>It is E who first introduced me to <em>Ecofeminism</em>. The idea of connecting Women and Nature, who are both under the yoke of dominant human males, was a bit far-fetched yet fascinating due to its mystical spirituality that she loved. By that time people just started to recover from covid, when female medical workers’ contribution was under-valued. She guided me through different schools of feminism, and we were proud to explore what we could do to revoke certain groups of people’s compromised positions.</p><p>How Kya fought from a repressed youth and seek nature as her natural company delivered a perfect portrait of Ecofeminism. Stereotypically, women and nature always co-habit harmoniously, while the combination of men and nature often implies conquer. Love the words Kya said: “I don’t know if there’s a dark side to nature, just inventive ways to endure.” She endured, and she fought smartly. For a moment I was disappointed that she married that guy who abandoned her once, but then I realized perhaps I’m not in the right position to judge.</p><p>Back to <strong><em>Elementary</em></strong>. I watched its first episode countless times years ago when it piloted. An Asian female Watson was never appealing to me, and now it seems funny that a female Watson could have pure friendship yet other same-sex modern Holmes-Watson duo usually contains sexual innuendos.</p><p>After that there were some big life decisions (or shall I say delay?). I finished season 1 of <strong><em>Masters of Sex</em></strong>. Interestingly my friends usually know <strong>Michael Sheen</strong> from <strong><em>Good Omens</em></strong>, but for me he is the scum lawyer Roland Blum in <strong><em>The Good Fight</em></strong>. The stories of discovering the mechanism of orgasms and women’s fight for improving status in sexual behaviors and workplace were truly inspiring, but the series lack some drama that could push to watch on. Same happened to <strong><em>The Marvelous Mrs. Maisel</em></strong>, which I skipped the last season.</p><p>Similar topics, <strong><em>Sex Education</em></strong> is my favorite series which I finished the last season in early December. I watched the first season in astonishment while being quarantined in Leuven. What a sex Utopia it is! Gladly we had a great biology teacher who vividly taught us how to us condoms, and we should do more to educate young people how to respect our partners, ask and listen to each other’s needs and feelings, and be open to pioneer ideologies. Happily, knowledges were learnt, mistakes I had were pointed out, and some tips were even put into practice. I’m proud to quote that “we don’t restrain ourselves into biological gender roles and we explore, communicate, and respect what we like as two sexual comrades.”</p><p>I always imagine that I were the leading male character in shows I love. So, when Issac deleted Otis’ message, it marked the lowest point of my Leuven months. Anyway, I had expressed to E many times that in case of gender equality, I do believe in over-compensating the ‘repressed-side.’  I was glad to see Maeve finally decided to stay abroad and pursue her dreams while Otis was still somehow immature and stuck in his little hometown. Also, I truly resonate with Maeve’s last letter to Otis – “dear you, you cracked my heart open, you introduced me to an equal, unconventional, empathic relationship, and I will never be that bit-traditional-head young guy again, and I will carry a part of you with me wherever I go.”</p><p>Through out the year I watched a lot of <strong>Marvel</strong> productions, but all of them were extremely terrible, including <strong><em>Loki 2</em></strong>, which was quite well-received online recently. In the past years my favorite one was <strong><em>Shang-Chi</em></strong>, which has a better-than-average plot and perfect spoken mandarin. Sadly, <strong>Simu Liu</strong> looks too much like our Big Brother.</p><p>-—– midsession break ——</p><p>Honorable mentions: LC recommended two movies that we watched during summer. <strong><em>1898 Los últimos de Filipinas</em></strong>, a Spanish film about the empire’s last days holding their Philippine colonies, and <strong><em>El Norte</em></strong>, a tragic story of a Guatemalan brother-sister duo who fled their homeland for United States, where immigrant fantasy eventually was shattered.</p><p>-—– midsession break ——</p><p><strong><em>Vigil</em></strong> season 1. I kind of developed a taste for lesbian romance. I like <strong>Rose Leslie</strong>, aka Ygritte in the <strong><em>Game of Thrones</em></strong>. She already delivered an outstanding performance of <strong>Maia</strong> in the <strong><em>Good Fight</em></strong> as a lesbian lawyer. Watching submarine&#x2F;enclose space-related shows in Munger room was quite a unique experience.</p><p><strong><em>Reds</em></strong>, an American film about their most famous socialist activist and journalist John Salis “Jack” Reed, made me cry. It was produced in the 80s, thus it was still during cold war. The story focused on Reed and his partner Louise, and their adventures reporting WWI and the Russian revolution. I was still in the break-up mood that time, and the scene of Jack and Louise, comrades and lovers, holding hands in Eastern Europe prairie, against the strong winds, irritating sands and heavy snows, against all the odds, is the most ideal representation of a romantic relationship, and I feel that I once had that.</p><p>There seems be a lot about feminism. On plane to the US I watched <strong><em>Barbie</em></strong> and <strong><em>Little Women</em></strong> (2019). I believe one of the core ideas is to give confidence to people who were systematically discouraged, and to offer equal or even more opportunities. Allan, and some other details, perfectly demonstrated that people are not born women but becoming women. I myself, having been in compromised or vulnerable positions several times, either voluntarily or unwillingly, may have encountered something similar and been somehow able to sympathize. Interestingly <strong><em>Barbie</em></strong> and <strong><em>Sex Education</em></strong> share a great number of cast members. By the way, I recently had a huge crush on Irish accent and people overall. <strong>Saoirse Ronan</strong> motivated me to watch <strong><em>Little Women</em></strong>, O played by <strong>Thaddea Graham</strong>, a Northen Irish adopted Hunanese actor, has such a lovely accent, and Mark Allen the professional snooker player from Northen Ireland has the sexist voice when he is doing game commentary.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Movies and TV</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>Ecofemenism</tag>
      
      <tag>John Reed</tag>
      
      <tag>Sex Education</tag>
      
      <tag>Where the Crawdads Sing</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Not Shawshank</title>
    <link href="/2023/12/28/1228/"/>
    <url>/2023/12/28/1228/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Back to AA</p><p>I had a colleague at K, who is a PhD student in THU and has been working as an intern there for more than 3 years.<br>Interestingly, though having these years in industry, he is desperate to find a teaching job (ideally AP) in a top university. A 211+ school in or near Beijing, to be specific, as his GF is already working in Beijing.<br>I could not get his mindset, and at my final day I asked him why. Why you must be a professor, why not make more money in industry, why it must be Beijing?<br>“Have you watched Shawshank? I want to be institutionalized.”<br>I was quite shocked.<br>To me he is already the opposition to many of my ideal principles: don’t let your partner ‘limit’ your choice, choose the money job if the other is about love, choose a different place for your next journey, …etc, but at that moment his “institutionalized” words sounded really courageous to me.<br>You see? Of course I personally do not want to be institutionalized, such as doing same things every day, having the same un-evolving mindset through the years, but partly it’s because I perhaps am not ready for some more responsibility. And those unconventional and crazy thoughts of mine, are they partly serving as a run-away from some more real and imminent challenges?<br>It’s 5+ years into adulthood now. Based on those years’ interaction and observation, we seemed to have formed some quite different life styles and ideologies, but I guess lots of us are still seeking and ready to change.<br>F.Y.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Self-Mumbling</category>
      
      <category>Early Days</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Kaiserreich (1)</title>
    <link href="/2023/12/26/1227/"/>
    <url>/2023/12/26/1227/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Flying in 8 hours.</p><p>So, there was another conversation. “Don’t be fooled by that vulnerability ‘chicken-soup’.” It’s always about Migliorare, about being stronger, and always an independent journey since long long ago.</p><p>I left with a promise to talk about Huey Long, so here it is.</p><p>My obsession to <a href="https://kaiserreich.fandom.com/wiki/The_Kaiserreich_Wiki">Kaiserreich</a>, a HOI4 game mod, started since last year in college till this June. It came with that so-called “political depression” I had regarding the changing world. The mod provided a perfect platform where one may explore a whole spectrum of ideologies and alternate situation.</p><p>Huey Long, in particular, is one of the options, a fascinating path. To be concise, in a short 33-year life, he grew from a country boy to a respected lawyer, then politician, governor, and finally being shot as senator. Being accused of de-facto dictatorship, he greatly promoted the well-being of Louisianna, boosted education, infrastructure, and social equality. He was on the road to his dream: “every man a king”, but was sadly shot on the way.</p><p>That day when I was visiting the congress building, wandering on the streets of Baton Rouge, people all showed their pity and respect to that legendary leader. Yet the style of the magnificent tower, the authority of statues, and the quasi-insane enthusiasm once people had towards him are quite dangerous.</p><p>Long, along with Jack Reed, are the most profound inspirations I got from Kaiserreich. “Man, a life like that? Totally worth it.”</p><p>But why I could not find someone in the OTL that makes me feel the same way(Peng Huang, maybe)? Perhaps it’s the idea of “having a second chance in the alternate universe.” A mixed-legendary-tragic life in OTL, and a could-have-been perfect fantasy in KR, somehow compensated for the uncertainty of my unpredictable future.</p><p>There’s a lot more to talk about Long, Reed, and other KR&#x2F;political admiration I had, but those feelings faded a little in recent months, partly thanks to a busy schedule and an improving mentality. Nonetheless, I do decide to continue to read and learn from them, figuring out if there’s something I can do in this 2020s that is as full of uncertainties, turmoil, and opportunities as 100 years ago was.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Self-Mumbling</category>
      
      <category>Early Days</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>Huey Long</tag>
      
      <tag>Kaiserreich</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Books (early years)</title>
    <link href="/2023/03/22/0322/"/>
    <url>/2023/03/22/0322/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Ok, a bit later than planned.</p><p>It was a great trip to Louisiana, though the competition result was not that good, spending times with old partners and teammates was never boring, and the extra adventure to Baton Rouge was nice. I’ll talk about Huey Long next time.</p><p>I promised to talk about books.</p><p>A huge portion of books I read is detective novels.  When I was very young, one of the first books I read was Sherlock Holmes in Chinese. I never managed to finish all of the stories but reading it was really cool and satisfying, as, to be honest, seeming to be intelligent was real sexy.</p><p>But I did not read a lot for a long time, I could name less than ten books that moved me and were read completely by me before Gaosan. Kuerliulangji, the first book my dad bought for me; Sanguoyanyi, reading it as a by-product of obsessed with Sanguosha; Shuihuzhuan, another try to classics as Sanguo turned out well; Pingfandeshijie, kinda felt related because I was in a relationship; Langtuteng, kinda obsessed with mysteries; Sishitongtang, during the rebellious Chusan; Harry Potter, the first time I read in English seriously.</p><p>During that time, most of other readings were tedious and boring to me. The first attempt for English book by myself was The Death On the Nile I bought at an airport. Sadly there was a reading report I had to hand in as the winter vacation homework so I read the plot summary on Wikipedia and ended up only reading 50% of the book.</p><p>Nonetheless, it was a great book. By that time I was still having trouble remembering the characters’ names of any foreign book. Also, I have an obsession of reading the ‘big names’. I guess it was the part of the education I received. ‘Always read the classics’. I kept looking for the most famous detective novelists, some ‘top 100’ books lists, and bought all of them to satisfy both my greed for intriguing plots and my pride.</p><p>Agatha Christie is the biggest part of the list, then John Dickson Carr, Ellery Queen (still waiting to read the tragedies trilogy). Other writer I would only read few so-called ‘best’ ones, like Raymond Chandler, Lawrence Block, Josephine Tey, etc. I guess I only care for the classics part of the detective novels, mostly from US and UK. I know nowadays Japanese novels are dispensable in detective novels market, but I never bothered to check any of them, as I only tried a book from their pioneer Edogawa Rampo.</p><p>The best detective novels I read in Chinese is 1367 by the Hong Kong man Chen Haoji. The time I enjoyed reading it coincided with the political movements happening in HK in 2019. Combining those politics, colonization, duty, police, self-identification, revolution (1967) topics really intrigued me.</p><p>Well, I am a bit sick back from traveling, that’s all for today.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Books</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Who Am I? (2018)</title>
    <link href="/2021/01/31/who-am-i-2018/"/>
    <url>/2021/01/31/who-am-i-2018/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>When I was writing my application letters for graduate school yesterday, I found this “Personal Statement” I wrote for HKU application three years ago. It was a week after Gaokao, and I could estimate that my score would not be good enough, so I wrote this PS casually but devotedly. It is a story about Beijing and Changsha, about my identity, and it’s still worth reading.</em></p><p>Personal Statement</p><p>Who am I</p><p>June 8th, 2018, after finishing Gaokao, I took the late flight from Changsha to Beijing to reunite with my schoolmates and take graduation photograph. This trip was hard to define. Was it a trip BACK home? Or did I just fly TO Beijing? Logically speaking, I live in Beijing, so it is my home. Geographically and emotionally speaking , my hometown is Changsha, the place where I was born. So, whenever a university asked me where I come from, I would hesitate, then answer “maybe Beijing” and think that perhaps anywhere would be my home.</p><p>In Beijing, I am proud to be a Hunanese. Though my identity set difficulties for me to attend high school in Beijing and disallowed me to take Gaokao in Beijing, I am not embarrassed with this situation. I embraced my education and expressed my talents. I luckily attend a great primary school by my parents’ efforts; I was chosen in the Early Development Program of RDFZ for talented students; I performed well in Zhongkao and successfully continued my education in high school. In my life, there is a voice that keeps telling me to inherit the Four Spirit of Changsha people, which are perseverance, bravery, patience, and optimism. I carried these spirits to stand out in my circle and carried these spirits to get on well with things around me, proving that I am strong enough to survive in Beijing.</p><p>I miss my hometown in Beijing, missing the food, the accents, the weather, everything. However, when I went back to Changsha to take Gaokao, I found that I got lost in my hometown. My new classmates treated me more as a Beijinger than a local fellow, and they were surprised to hear dialectical words and Hunanese accent from my speaking. At that time, I was a little bit disappointed, since it seemed that I was not fully accepted by neither Beijing nor Changsha.</p><p>Confused, I began to think that whether the environment accepts me is not a major problem, as the real question is that what I accept myself as. Fortunately, the experience in Changsha in last few months provided me a great chance to rethink my path. Being far away from Beijing, still not familiar with new friends and classmates, I got a better condition to observe things around me.</p><p>Honestly, what I received in Beijing, in RDFZ, is a quite liberal education that allowed me to pursue what I am interested in with the smallest limit. I met baseball, I found Bridge, and I was even allowed to climb up to the dangerous roof of school building to make movie. By contrast, in Changsha, the administration on students is believed to be stricter. However, I am not saying that one condition is better than the other. I encountered the authentic spirits during my stay in Changsha. The spirits were not just in Hunanese’s mind. They put them into action: the dedication in study, the ambition to leave Hunan, represent Hunan, and make contribution to our country as a Hunanese.</p><p>I came to a conclusion that why I felt strange in both two cities is that maybe I have qualities from both cities. That conclusion excites me and encourages me to continue my life path with my treasured experience and spirits.</p><p>Now I am standing on the crossroads to universities. I always believe a new place would be a great choice. Hong Kong is the metropolitan that attracts me. I have been there for countless times for SAT exams, for Bridge competitions, and for holiday trips. I even founded a Cantonese Culture Club in high school two years ago. Hong Kong has a more liberal environment, a warm and humid climate of southern China, an intricate metro system, and a diverse language environment mixing Cantonese, Mandarin and English that I longed for.</p><p>All in all, I believe that wherever I go, I will keep my pride as a Hunanese, and more importantly, as a person who treats everywhere as his home.   </p><p>First written on 15&#x2F;06&#x2F;2018, Beijing.</p><p>Edited on 31&#x2F;01&#x2F;2021, Roma</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Self-Mumbling</category>
      
      <category>Who Am I</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Remember Fabio Carli (花比傲)——The &#39;Marco Polo&#39; in Chinese pop music history</title>
    <link href="/2019/04/15/remember-fabio-carli-%E8%8A%B1%E6%AF%94%E5%82%B2-the-modern-marco-polo-in-chinese-music-history/"/>
    <url>/2019/04/15/remember-fabio-carli-%E8%8A%B1%E6%AF%94%E5%82%B2-the-modern-marco-polo-in-chinese-music-history/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://yfq32.files.wordpress.com/2019/04/fabio-e1555411932808.jpg"></p><p>Fabio Carli</p><p>“Queen’s Road East”(皇后大道东): 1991,<br>the most famous Cantonese song about the handover of Hong Kong, describes the<br>worries, excitement, hesitation, and expectation of local people in humorous lyrics.<br>‘My dear friends, bidding goodbye, left this metropolis and went afar, and now<br>we gonna depend on the great comrades to cook up some new ideas.’</p><p>“Pear of the Orient”(东方之珠):<br>1991, the Iconic song celebrating the handover of Hong Kong, is a chant for the<br>city’s unrest past and prosperous future. ‘For five thousand years, the sea<br>wind blows. Please remember my face, forever yellow.’</p><p>“Old Friend Seems To Be<br>Coming”(似是故人来): 1992, one of the best song of the ‘pop queen’ Anita Mui(梅艳芳).</p><p>……</p><p>All these unforgettable songs, which marked the peak of Hong Kong pop music and witnessed the legendary 1990s of China, are arranged by an Italian musician: Fabio Carli.</p><p>Fabio Carli was born in<br>Ronchi dei Legionari, Italy, in 1951. He founded a band called ‘I Cobra’ and<br>went on tour in Europe by covering some successful works of Lucio Battisti<br>and New Trolls. Then he started travelling around the world. He went to<br>Dubai, Taipei, Tokyo, Sydney, and finally interestingly, spent his most<br>important 11 years in Hong Kong (1986-1997).</p><p><img src="https://yfq32.files.wordpress.com/2019/04/e7bd97e5a4a7e4bd91.jpg"></p><p>Fabio and 罗大佑, via sina.com</p><p>One year after Fabio’s<br>arrival, Lo Da-Yu(罗大佑) ended his 2-year stay in U.S. and decided to continue his music<br>career in Hong Kong. The two “foreigners” hit it off in the metropolis. Their<br>first song is “Rebirth”(轮回) in 1989. Lo composed, and<br>Fabio arranged. Lo said: “We were both ‘outsiders’, so we dared to challenge the<br>local traditions and taboos. We played music together in HK, the city where<br>East meets West, Left meets Right.”  </p><p>In 1990, Lo founded Music<br>Factory, which is a milestone in Chinese music history. In the Factory, Lo, who<br>composed, Fabio, who arranged, and Albert Leung(林夕), who<br>wrote lyrics, created countless Cantonese and Mandarin songs that are praised<br>as the best of all times.</p><p>“花比傲”, Fabio’s<br>Chinese name was given by Leung at the same time. The name’s Cantonese pronunciation<br>(Faa-bei-ngou) is very close to the original, and it comes from Chinese poems which<br>means “flower and pride”, so romantic.</p><p>Leung describe Fabio as a<br>man who not only “loves Chinese culture, and can create music with Chinese<br>style”, but also “can treat Chinese elements from a critical and innovative<br>point of view”, which makes their works seem “less traditional and more<br>energetic”.</p><p><img src="https://yfq32.files.wordpress.com/2019/04/e69e97e5a495.jpg"></p><p>Fabio and 林夕, via sina.com</p><p>Lo left HK in 1995, and<br>afterwards Fabio bid his goodbye to HK in 1997. He became a photographer and director<br>in New York and even won some awards. He went back to Italy and died of cancer<br>on April 15th, 2013, 6 years ago. His last song is called “Stranger<br>in my town”, included his whole colorful music life.</p><p>Some days ago, I just<br>figured out his full name on Internet, and was surprised to find that he is an<br>Italian and shares the same last name as LUISS. Here, I’m writing this brief<br>article on his Memorial Day, just to express my love for the music of that time<br>and my respect to all the musicians, singers, and writers who created so many<br>wonderful melodies to us.</p><p><img src="https://yfq32.files.wordpress.com/2019/04/arr.png"></p><p>Leung, Lo, Carli<br>Songwriter, composer, arranger</p><p>Although many Chinese people may not remember him and even mistake him as a Chinese guy, Fabio Carli, the modern ‘Marco Polo’ in music, undoubtedly has made a great contribution to HK music society, and the work of him, Lo, and Leung will be played forever.  </p><p>元芳 2019年4月16日凌晨 于罗马</p><p>(</p><p>Thanks to Diego, who helped<br>me find some information in Italian about Fabio Carli.</p><p>For those who don’t know Lo Da-Yu<br>and Albert Leung, please remember them as the most important men in Chinese pop<br>music history.</p><p>To me, the best work of<br>Fabio is 来自你,来自我,来自他(“From you,<br>from me, from everyone”). It is both composed and arranged by Fabio so it’s<br>rare and precious.</p><p>For those who are<br>interested, here are some links for articles and Youtube, which are also my<br>reference for this blog:</p><p>皇后大道东 Queen’s Road East：</p><p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UYzQEObtujA">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UYzQEObtujA</a></p><p>Lyrics translation in English: <a href="https://sites.google.com/site/cmhubertchen/html/queens/_road/_east">https://sites.google.com/site/cmhubertchen/html/queens\_road\_east</a></p><p>东方之珠 Pear of the Orient：</p><p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vRG919KG4vc">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vRG919KG4vc</a></p><p>Lyrics translation in English:  <a href="http://www.chinesetolearn.com/pearl-orient-dong-fang-zhi-zh/">http://www.chinesetolearn.com/pearl-orient-dong-fang-zhi-zh/</a></p><p>来自你来自我来自他：</p><p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=V9_kdUzTaVs">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=V9_kdUzTaVs</a></p><p>Stranger in my Town:</p><p><a href="https://vimeo.com/36982087">https://vimeo.com/36982087</a></p><p>L’articolo su di lui in Italiano:</p><p><a href="http://ricerca.gelocal.it/ilpiccolo/archivio/ilpiccolo/2015/05/03/provincia-rivive-in-una-serata-a-tutto-sound-fabio-carli-fondatore-dei-cobra-47.html">http://ricerca.gelocal.it/ilpiccolo/archivio/ilpiccolo/2015/05/03/provincia-rivive-in-una-serata-a-tutto-sound-fabio-carli-fondatore-dei-cobra-47.html</a></p><p>Two articles in Chinese<br>remembering him:</p><p><a href="http://www.hkcd.com/content/2016-04/25/content/_997410.html">http://www.hkcd.com/content/2016-04/25/content\_997410.html</a></p><p><a href="http://blog.renren.com/share/238615339/15864700907">http://blog.renren.com/share/238615339/15864700907</a></p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Music and Society</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>罗大佑</tag>
      
      <tag>Fabio Carli</tag>
      
      <tag>Hong Kong</tag>
      
      <tag>林夕</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Visit the cemetery of Italo Calvino——and a story between him and a young Chinese student</title>
    <link href="/2019/01/11/visit-the-cemetery-of-italo-calvino-and-a-story-between-him-and-a-young-chinese-student/"/>
    <url>/2019/01/11/visit-the-cemetery-of-italo-calvino-and-a-story-between-him-and-a-young-chinese-student/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Forward: This article is about my journey to <strong>Castiglione della Pescaia</strong> and why I like <strong>Italo Calvino</strong>. I wrote in English since I hope more people can read it. All the pictures used in the article are copyright of myself. If there is any grammar mistake or cultural and semantic confusion, please feel free to point out.</p><p><img src="https://yfq32.files.wordpress.com/2019/01/img_20181001_194847-1.jpg" alt="A copy of Il Barone Rampante, photoed by yfq32"></p><p><strong>Italo Calvino</strong> is my favorite foreign writer. (and I will tell you why later) Therefore, this winter vacation in Italy, my very first thing to do is visiting him. Having been searching information online, I figured out that there is no museum or memorial place for him. Thanks to <a href="https://www.ruanyifeng.com/calvino/">“Italo Calvino in China”</a>, <a href="https://www.findagrave.com/">“Find a Grave”</a>, and a local tourist website, I got to know where his cemetery lies——Castiglione della Pescaia, right on the coast where <strong>Mr. Palomar watched and meditated the waves of the sea.</strong></p><p>Without anything found in detail, I set the address (<strong>Cimitero di Castiglione della Pescaia</strong>) on Google Map and hit the road.</p><p>On 21st Dec 2018, I took train at 6:57 AM from <strong>Roma Termini to Grosseto</strong>. The train took around and 1.5 hour and later at 9:30, I got on the <strong>Extraurbana</strong> bus to Castiglione della Pescaia.</p><p>That day had the bluest sky. I, the only passenger on the bus, along with the friendly driver, was free to enjoy the endless grassland and Mediterranean pine trees beside the road. Staring at these trees with wide branches reaching to the others, I suddenly realized what <strong>Cosimo Piovasco di Rondò</strong> did may not be so difficult.</p><p><img src="https://yfq32.files.wordpress.com/2019/01/img_20181221_101154.jpg" alt="On the road, by yfq32"></p><p>After bus, I still had a mile to go. <strong>I walked on the ancient roads, passed the lovely bars, and wandered through a castle</strong>. The public cemetery is located on the mountainside, with a great view of the town on the east side and the sea on the west side. Only few people were there, and I crept silently around looking for where Italo Calvino is.</p><p><img src="https://yfq32.files.wordpress.com/2019/01/img_20181221_102839.jpg" alt="On the mountainside, by yfq32"></p><p>Finally, a <strong>staff</strong> approached me. He seemed <strong>confused</strong> to see a Chinese face in an Italian cemetery, but when I told him who I was looking for, he led me to the tombstone <strong>excitingly</strong>.</p><p>Maybe I am one of the <strong>first</strong> Chinese readers to ever come here. The tomb looked the same as the picture I found online, only without the bush around it. Calvino’s wife, <strong>Esther Judith Singer</strong>, was on the left side with him. There were branches and stones placed on it, and a slight layer of dust. <strong>The mountains, sky, sea, birds, and the ticking of water drops in the cemetery, created a great harmony of nature.</strong></p><p><img src="https://yfq32.files.wordpress.com/2019/01/img_20181221_104201.jpg" alt="Calvino and Singer, by yfq32"></p><p>I silently expressed my <strong>respect and admiration</strong>, placed <strong>a bottle cap and a diamond-shape stone</strong> which represent my nickname, and left.</p><p>I spent some time pacing on the beach. After people-watching and a so-called meditation, I left.</p><p><img src="https://yfq32.files.wordpress.com/2019/01/img_20181221_105053.jpg" alt="by yfq32"></p><p>At 10th grade in high school, my friend and I found <strong>a secret ladder</strong> tube to the <strong>roof</strong> of the senior building. We enjoyed climbing through it in day and night, exploring the secret of the top of the building, chatting, and laughing. We even came there on a freezing rainy night, just standing and watching the skyscrapers of Beijing in the distance and the people under our feet, and on a snowy winter day, just playing snowball and yelling. I was sort of <strong>addicted</strong> to that kind of experience and began to spend lots of time exploring other roofs on my school campus. I called these roofs the <strong>“Sacred Land”</strong> for my friend and I. The land <strong>for adventures, for temporary escape from the reality, for recalling the past, for meditation, for sincere conversation, for people-watching from a different point of view, for sitting in daze and daydreaming.</strong></p><p>I regarded what I did as a <strong>“run-away”</strong> of an individual. It can be simply seen as a <strong>rebellious act</strong>, or maybe there is some symbolic and metaphysical meaning underneath. I made a documentary movie called <a href="https://www.bilibili.com/video/BV1Wx41167hB/"><strong>“The Sacred Land”</strong></a> to remember all those <strong>crazy roof top adventures</strong>, and entered my last year of high school.</p><p><img src="https://yfq32.files.wordpress.com/2019/01/%E5%9C%A3%E5%9C%B0%E5%89%A7%E7%85%A7%E6%88%91%E6%8B%8D.jpg" alt="yfq32 on the roof of RDFZ senior high building, photoed by YJY"></p><p>The 12th grade was when I came across Calvino’s books. At that time, I was curious to look for some famous contemporary and modern <strong>Italian writers</strong>. I got <strong>“if on a winter night a traveler”</strong> in bookstore (<strong>Douban Bookstore</strong> on Chengfu Road, Beijing) and began reading <strong>“our ancestors”</strong> trilogy later.</p><p>I was <strong>shocked</strong> to encounter the story of Cosimo in “Baron in the trees”. <strong><em>“That’s me!”</em></strong>. My adventures on the roofs was the <strong>modern version</strong> of Cosimo’s, though I still live on ground and can’t move from a roof to another freely. However, I realized, in some metropolis where skyscrapers are everywhere and <strong>linked</strong> with overpasses, some people do live a life <strong>without touching the ground and forever</strong> in the buildings. Their lives could be more physically enriched than Cosimo’s since the modern technology ensures a safer, more convenient, and comfortable environment than in trees, but the interest of <strong>leaving your group life and living your life</strong> with your human fellows as whole from a <strong>perfect distance</strong> is the key, to which I believe I experienced thing <strong>similar</strong>.</p><p>Later, I went to another school in <strong>south</strong>, where trees were <strong>denser and greener</strong>. I got a great chance to study my previous and recent school lives from a perfect distance. Cosimo’s life can be regard as a process <strong>from individual to integrity</strong>, and I tried to do the same on me and my surroundings. Anyway, I keep looking for the similarity and difference <strong>between me and Cosimo</strong> and adding more quotes to our lives.</p><p><img src="https://yfq32.files.wordpress.com/2019/01/img_20180420_181946999999999.jpg" alt="Trees in my school (HNSDFZ), by yfq32"></p><p>I have read <strong>almost all</strong> Calvino’s works in Chinese and English translation, and I am learning Italian to enjoy the original ones. He is not only a great writer to me, <strong>he shared his thoughts with me</strong>. He has many great works in different styles and today is not the time for me to discuss further. Now, allow me to use his words in “Il Barone Rampante” to remember Italo Calvino: <strong>Visse sugli alberi - Amò sempre la terra - Salì in cielo</strong>.</p><p>2019.01.11 by 元芳 yfq32</p><p>2025.01.18 edited</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Books</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>Baron in the trees</tag>
      
      <tag>Castiglione della Pescaia</tag>
      
      <tag>Cosimo Piovasco di Rondò</tag>
      
      <tag>Italo Calvino</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  
</search>
